<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
<title>Blog</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/</link>
<description>kasun gamlath personal site</description>

<item>
<title>Fixing Garmin Fenix HR Sensor</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2025-05-11-Fixing-Garmin-Fenix-HR-Sensor/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I bought a Garmin Fenix 6 on 2021 November.
Around 2023 April, HR sensor stopped working.
I assumed it's a software issue, and tried various fixes including 1) soft/hard resetting. 2) upgrading/downgrading firmware &amp; software.
But nothing fixed it.
At the end I settled to buy a Garmin HR chest strap on 2024 June.
This setup worked well for workouts, but strap is not comfortable to wear all the time, so I'd still miss on the always on heart rate sensor.</p>
<p>When I was researching the issue while most of the resources suggested this is a software issue, there were few saying this could be a loose cable.
But I was hesitant to take the watch apart and didn't pay much attention to this possibility, until this week.</p>
<p>Last week was the final week of my busiest school term so far (both as a student and instructor).
Once the final grading frenzy was over (with much vigor) I started working on all the fun stuff I wanted to do but didn't have a time to.
This included 1) buying a drone 2) buying a mini PC (to set up as a home server).
When I was doing all this shopping, at some point I found myself comparing the Apple Watch Ultra and Watch 10. (By this time I'm convinced the issue is a software issue and didn't want to invest in Garmin products anymore)
Then it occurred to me if I'm to buy a new watch, why not try and re-seat the cable.</p>
<p>So yesterday I turned the watch off and took it apart.
I removed the backplate first, but the cable was not accessible from the back.
I put the backplate back, turned on the watch to check the watch is still working.
Turning the watch off again, removed the front panel.
Removed both cables visible, cleaned them using an alcohol solution and reseated them.
(HR sensor cable is the one marked by a star. Photo credit: reddit user &quot;Lobomute&quot;)</p>
<p><img src="/assets/garmin.webp" alt="" /></p>
<p>Then re-screwed the front panel back, and turned the watch back on.
And I believe this is the happiest I've being after seeing a blinking green light (HR sensor blink green when trying to find the wrist).
Just like that, after two years of a comma HR sensor is up and working again.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/garmin_working.jpg" alt="" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How I Got My Security Deposit Back</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2025-03-20-How-I-Got-My-Security-Deposit-Back/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I had trouble getting the security deposit back from my previous landlord. (He doesn't own the property, act as the main tenant)</p>
<p>When I requested the security deposit (SGD 1450) at end of the tenancy period, I got a reply that it’s denied because of some (alleged) damages I caused.
Though I was expecting this kind of response (given the experiences of other tenants) it still came as a shock, and I replied I’ll file a case (in SCT) unless they return my deposit back.
Right after this, they made a claim against me requesting SGD 3510 (minus deposit) in SCT.
Their breakdown as follows,</p>
<ul>
<li>Repair of scratched floor - $900</li>
<li>Repair of cupboard scuffs - $200</li>
<li>Changing and Repair of Broken Door - $400</li>
<li>Changing and Fixing of Broken Power Outlet - $200</li>
<li>1 Month Loss of Rental Income - $1,450</li>
</ul>
<p>I’m still not sure why they went ahead and filed the case first.
Because as I see it, there’s no way their claims hold in a court (or any reasonable person buying it for that matter).
Maybe they were trying to intimidate me with a court order.
Or maybe they were trying to play victim and get the court to favor them by filing the case first.
It's also possible they were just trying to delay the payment, since the claimant get to pick the first consultation date.</p>
<p>The SCT work like this.</p>
<ol>
<li>Claimant files a claim (with a defects schedule) and pick the fist consultation date.
(And they have to serve the court notice to respondent within seven days.)</li>
<li>Respondent reply to the defects schedule, prior to the first consultation.</li>
<li>At the first consultation (physical or online), claimant and respondent meet in front of the court registrar.
Registrar explains process of the court and hear from both parties.</li>
<li>Depending on the situation registrar recommends another consultation, mediation or trial.</li>
<li>If the suggestion is another consultation or mediation, both parties have to agree, else the case directly to a trial.</li>
</ol>
<p>First consultation was set on Dec 30th.
Three months after I moved out, and two months after I requested the deposit.
(This is why I assumed they were trying to delay the payment)</p>
<p>While waiting for the consultation, I talked with few friends and colleagues, and looked up on the court process.
I also replied to the defect schedule they file in the SCT.
I already had photos of the floor at the beginning of the tenancy period, and I said other defects are hardly noticeable and at any case should be considered as normal wear and tear except for the power plug.
The power plug I replied, is working when I moved out. (as I found out later, it's still working. The new tenant didn't check it properly)
For the loss of rental income I replied, since I’m not responsible for any of the damages I’m not liable.</p>
<p>The first consultation date arrived, and I was quite nervous about it.
During the consultation registrar asked where we stand.
Claimant went first, and listed the damages I allegedly did.
When my turn came, I repeated what I submitted as reply to defect schedule, and evidence he provided doesn’t claim otherwise.
To this the other party replied they have more evidence.
After hearing this and checking the current state of evidences, registrar gave a deadline to other party to upload all the evidence, and set another consultation on 27th Jan.
This first consultation session started about 30 min late, and lasted for about an hour.</p>
<p>Second consultation was postponed to 3rd February.
(later I found out this is due to another court case regarding the security deposit with this landlord and another tenant)
Claimant didn’t manage to upload any new evidence, and during the consultation said they are ready to settle for 600 (150 SGD per each four defects).
By then it's clear to me, this is a fishing expedition from the claimant to retain (at least) part of the deposit or just to delay the payment.
I stood my ground and refused this offer.
I said I’ll only settle for the full deposit.</p>
<p>Other party requested one more day to consider this.</p>
<p>So a third consultation was arranged on following day, Feb 4th.</p>
<p>During this session, other party said they are willing to settle and agreed to return the full deposit within a month.
I said I’m okay with this arrangement and the court issued an order stating this final agreement.</p>
<p>On March 3rd (five months after moving out) I was paid the full deposit back.</p>
<p>Looking back it was quite a lot of work and mental energy spent to get what’s rightfully mine.
And the monetary value of the deposit wasn’t enough to cover this effort.</p>
<p>But I learned a lot from this experience, and I believe the things I learned, is worth the effort and getting the deposit back is only the icing of the cake.</p>
<h4>Timeline</h4>
<ul>
<li>30/09/2024 - I moved out</li>
<li>30/11/2024 - I request for the deposit via email</li>
<li>30/11/2024 - They respond via email, and filed a claim</li>
<li>07/11/2024 - They share the respondent copy with me via email</li>
<li>08/11/2024 - I respond to the claim, email and make a counter-claim in SCT</li>
<li>16/12/2024 - I sent the notice via Singpost registered mail</li>
<li>30/12/2024 - First consultation</li>
<li><del>27/01/2025</del> 03/02/2025 - Second consultation</li>
<li>04/02/2025 - Third consultation</li>
<li>03/03/2025 - I got the deposit back</li>
</ul>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>My Journey into Budgeting</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2025-03-06-My-Journey-into-Budgeting/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p><img src="/assets/budget-screenshot.png" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>I always get a guilty feeling when I buy a non-necessasity item.
Non-necessasity item is anything that I could do without.
A camera would be a perfect example for this - unless you’re a professional photographer.
While I blame this for the fact me growing up poor, no matter how frugal I am I get this guilty feeling when I’m spending.</p>
<p>As solution for this I decided to follow budget and track my expenses.
So when amygdala complains, frontal lobes have numbers to work to back the reasoning.
For reference amygdala is the part of brain that work with the feelings related stuff while frontal lobe is doing the reasoning.</p>
<p>So moving on to my solution,
In order to budget properly I need to see where I stand at any given time.
For that I need to record all my expenses.
I can’t automate recording since sometimes I pay with cash. (though that’s pretty rare, it happens).</p>
<p>So I need a mechanism to easily record expenses as they happen.
Then a way to double-check my entries periodically.</p>
<p>To record the expenses I created a Numbers sheet and a Apple shortcut.
I can invoke the shortcut from the home screen, and enter the amount + description of the expense.
Then shortcut will enter this data to the numbers' sheet with the current date and default category.
I could have modified the shortcut to ask the category and skip having a default category.
But 7/10 times my expense is on the default category.
So having a default seems a better trade-off</p>
<p>Then I’ve a script to scan the bank notifications and check those records with the manual entries.
It logs into a email account and parse all the email receipts related to expenses.
That reminds me, I’ve a separate email account which my expense receipts get forwarded to.
While this doesn’t check all the records it can cover more than 90% expenses in my case.</p>
<p>I’ve being doing this now for more than a year, and it involved lots of minor tweaks.
For example, I didn’t use a shortcut at the beginning.
With this system now I have a more understanding on my spending habits,
and more importantly my expenses are mostly guilt free.
(Though some of them were quite stupid in hindsight)</p>
<p>If you'd like to use this method, download the linked numbers file and copy the shortcut to your phone. You'll need to update the path to the numbers file in the shortcut.</p>
<p><a href="/assets/budget-template-2025-03.numbers">Link numbers sheet (figures are for illustrative purpose only)</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/ffd1d57a6d2a456381b95273b2c989c8">Link to Apple shortcut</a></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Local Latex</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2025-02-25-Local-Latex/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Last term I started using latex to make notes for the my masters course.
I started with overleaf.
Overleaf needs a whole screen to show the code and the output pdf comfortably.
So if I'm to look at the lecture slides, latext code, and output pdf I need a second monitor.</p>
<p>But since I prefer writing notes while sitting in a caffe, second monitor is not possible.
So I decided to look into another way to write latex.</p>
<p>Quick online search resulted in few articles of people using a <code>mactex</code> tex engine (I'm using a macbook) and <code>latex-workshop</code> extension with vscode.
Following one of those articles I installed the <code>basictex</code> downloaded from <a href="https://tug.org/mactex/morepackages.html">here</a></p>
<p>And installed the latex-workshop extension in vscode.
But it couldn't compile my tex code.</p>
<p>Turned out the <code>basictex</code> doesn't come with <code>latexmk</code> which is required for compiling the tex code.
To install the <code>latexmk</code>, first need to run <code>sudo tlmgr update --self</code>.
Then <code>latexmk</code> can be installed with <code>sudo tlmgr install latexmk</code>.</p>
<p>I also had to install following packages to make use some features required for the notes.</p>
<p><code>sudo tlmgr install blindtext titlesec footmisc</code></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Year 2024</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2025-01-05-Year-2024/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>There wasn't any big changes in Year 2024.
It's more like a continuation of 2023.
Thinking back, highlights of this year would be:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="/blog/2024-04-30-Bachata/">Joining a Bachata class</a> (And finding out I'm quite bad at dancing)</li>
<li><a href="/blog/2024-07-08-Walk-in-the-Park(s)">Doing 69 km walk over ~17 hours</a></li>
<li><a href="/blog/2024-07-17-Kota-Bharu">Taking ~17 hours Train ride</a></li>
<li><a href="blog/2024-12-02-Beach-Tennis-Tournament">Joining a Beach Tennis tournament for the first time</a><br />
<em>I'm the top ranked (and apparently only) Beach Tennis player in Sri Lanka.</em></li>
</ul>
<p>I did also signup for a marathon.
But got sick right before the marathon and wasn't able to run.</p>
<p>Following are the goals I set for 2024 and final state of them.</p>
<ul>
<li>✅ Go to 5 volunteer events - <em>Did 8 events as a photographer, totaling 45.25 hours</em></li>
<li>✅ Read 30 books (20/30) - <em>49 books (Including 15 Diary of Wimpy Kid books)</em></li>
<li>✅ Start dance course - <em>Completed 6 month course</em></li>
<li>❌ Travel to 1 new countries - <em>Though I did travel overseas multiple of times, I didn't travel to any new country</em></li>
<li>❌ Make an electronic photo magazine - <em>No excuse</em></li>
<li>❌ Run a full marathon under 5 hours - <em>Got sick</em></li>
</ul>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Notes on Learning and Planning in Intelligent Systems</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-12-26-Notes-on-Learning-and-Planning-in-Intelligent-Systems/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Last term my choice of subject (for the master's degree) was Learning and Planning in Intelligent Systems.
We were offered 3 choices, and I already have completed one of them.
So it's a choice between Machine Learning or this.</p>
<p>With my work schedule this module was the preferred choice.
But into few weeks, I noticed that I don't understand what's going on in the classroom.
The course is on Reinforcement Learning, and I was completely new to the subject.
The content is heavy on math which wasn't my forte.</p>
<p>Then came the first quiz which weighted 12.5% of the final grade.
And I only got 38%.</p>
<p>This made me realize I needed to make serious effort if I'm to successfully finish the module.
After that I spent few hours per week going through the slides, re-watching the lecture video and consulting ChatGPT/ Gemini to make these notes.
And these notes helped me quite a lot to understand the subject.
At the end I got a B for subject.
That means I got at least 74% of the final grade.</p>
<p>To me that was great progress from where I started.</p>
<p><a href="/assets/cs711.pdf">link to the notes</a></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cooking Again</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-12-02-Cooking-Again/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Last couple of months I was feeling pretty weak.
Then I lost about 2 kg of body weight (without trying !).
I attribute this to my diet.
I had increased amount of physical activity (I was training for a marathon), but my diet was not up to it.</p>
<p>And I was also concerned about the nutrition levels of the stuff I eat.
I was eating all three meals outside.
And none of them contained many vegetables.
But based on the health guidelines half of the plate should be filled from vegetables (and fruit).
And quarter from carbs and remaining from protein.</p>
<p>So yesterday I decided to make a change.
I started cooking again.
This is what I came up with.
It's chicken, eggs, broccoli and sweet potato.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/cooking-again.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>(Broccoli in the picture is not cooked properly, had to cook them again).
I'm planing to find more recipes and cook more and more.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Beach Tennis Tournament</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-12-02-Beach-Tennis-Tournament/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I Joined my first Beach Tennis Tournament this November.
And played in the mixed double category.</p>
<p>We won 1 out of 4 games.
And we almost lost the game we won.
We were down to 0-4 at one point.
The final score for winning game is 7-5.</p>
<p>For the rest it's 0-6, 1-6 and, 4-6.</p>
<p>I was quite stressed during the tournament.
And found hitting the ball harder than I usually do, causing it to go either long or wide.
The game felt way harder and tiring than when I play for fun.</p>
<p>Now I have a IFBT ranking. 2 to be precise. Though I've no idea why there are 2 rankings.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/ifbt-ranking.png" alt="full-width" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Confirmation Bias</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-10-29-Confirmation-Bias/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I recently noticed that I like to read, and tend to rate higher the books that already confirm my established biases.
Which in turn reinforces my biases and leading to a deeper bubble.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Doing Things For No Reason</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-09-19-Doing-Things-For-No-Reason/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Last Saturday night I went on a 39km long walk (with few of my friends).
Then on the following night I met a friend of a friend who asked me why I did that.
I couldn’t think of an answer at the moment and said something (I hope) witty.</p>
<p>But later, that got me thinking, why did I do the walk ?
The best answer I could come up with is, because I like walking.
But that didn’t feel like a valid reason.</p>
<p>And then it occurred to me, most of the stuff I do don’t have a “valid” reason.
I just do stuff for the sake of doing them.</p>
<p>Not as means to an end.</p>
<p>And the fact that I don’t know what I want for the most of the time, pairs nicely with this and may be the enabler for this.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to Not Snooze in the Morning</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-08-15-How-to-Not-Snooze-in-the-Morning/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>In the past there were many times I set the alarm for an early morning wake up, only to snooze it and sleep in.
It's like going to sleep as Dr. Jekyll and waking up as Mr. Hyde.</p>
<p>Usually these wake-ups were supposed to followed by some kind of self-improvement activity, like going for an early morning run or going to gym.</p>
<p>Then about a year ago, it occurred to me if I have any external force/reason to wake me up in the morning I have no trouble getting out of bed.
For example if I have an appointment in the morning I can wake up to the alarm.
The nature of the appointment doesn't matter, as far as it involves a third party, Mr. Hyde can be tamed.</p>
<p>This provided an insight to my problem.
I need external help to keep Mr. Hyde in check.
So I made arrangement with a friend and told him I'd buy him a lunch If I failed to show up in the gym at 0800 in the morning.
(To do this I'd need to wake up by 0630)
The choice of friend is not important as far as you don't like buying him/her lunch.
As a proof I'm to send him a photo of the gym clock.</p>
<p>Eventually this method gathered more followers.
<img src="/assets/blog/8am_gym.jpeg" alt="" /></p>
<p>Fast-forward to today and buying few lunches later, I'm happy to say this method work surprisingly well.
Now I frequently enjoy early morning runs and gym sessions.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Goodbye Year 1, Hello Year 2</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-08-14-Goodbye-Year-1,-Hello-Year-2/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>This week is the last of my first academic year (for my masters program), and my new career as an instructor.</p>
<p>Looking back it's exciting and rewarding year.
I completed 2 out of 6 courses required for the masters program.
And supported 3 different courses as an instructor.</p>
<p>Sitting in a class felt (for the lack of better word) &quot;weird&quot; at the beginning, on both sides.
It's 8+ years since I last sat in a class as a student and first time being an instructor.
During the first term I supported one course and took one course for the masters.</p>
<p>Second term was merely a continuation of the first, with slightly higher work load.
Work load was higher because I was supporting 2 subjects, compared to 1 in first.
And was learning a subject (information security) I'm not familiar with.</p>
<p>After the second term came the third which is the summer term/break.
Since my school doesn't offer any courses during the summer term I didn't have to actively support a course nor learn.
Given these two activities occupied the majority of my time during first two terms, I ended up with a lot of free time on my hand.
During this time I mainly did prepare for the course I'm about to support, and read about the course I planned to learn.</p>
<p>During summer term/break, I also played a bit of racket sports (mainly table tennis due to my recovering tennis elbow), <a href="/blog/Home-Trip/">traveled home</a>, <a href="/blog/Walk-in-the-Park(s)/">walked across Singapore</a>, <a href="/blog/Kota-Bharu/">took a train to the boarder of Thailand via Malaysia</a>, and <a href="/photos/">took lots of photos</a>.</p>
<p>And from what I have seen so far, I expect the coming year to be more or less a repetition of the last.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Pita Bread</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-07-19-Pita-Bread/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Yesterday I made Pita bread (for the first time). Following the guidance of chef TOM.</p>
<h3>Ingredients</h3>
<ul>
<li>1kg plain flour</li>
<li>600 ml water</li>
<li>12 grams of yeast</li>
<li>35 grams sugar</li>
<li>5 (big) spoons of olive oil</li>
<li>1 (big) spoon salt</li>
</ul>
<h3>Process</h3>
<ol>
<li>Mix the dry ingredients</li>
<li>Add water + olive oil to the mix</li>
<li>Knead to a ball</li>
<li>Leave for at least 1 hour</li>
<li>Separate the dough to little balls
<img src="/assets/pita/balls.jpg" alt="" /></li>
<li>Role them flat (use dry flour to make it not stick)
<img src="/assets/pita/flat.jpg" alt="" /></li>
<li>Leave them for 10 minutes</li>
<li>Pre heat the oven to 240 with pan inside (need the pan to be hot in order to burn the sides of pita)</li>
<li>Place the flatted dough in the pan for 2-3 min (until they puff up)</li>
<li>Flip the flatted dough and leave it for another 1-2 min</li>
<li>Enjoy the pita bread !!!
<img src="/assets/pita/final.jpg" alt="" /></li>
</ol>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Kota Bharu</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-07-17-Kota-Bharu/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p><img src="/assets/kb_trip/kb-photospot.jpg" alt="wide" />
Last weekend me and a friend took a trip to north of Malaysia, via the east coast railway line.
This railway line is referred as the Jungle Railway and considered one of the most iconic rail lines in Asia.
Train trip from southern Malaysia (Johor Baru) starts at 2030 and finishes at Tumpat after a 17 hours long journey.</p>
<p>We went to Johor Baru (JB) on a Thursday evening to catch the train.
Train starts from JB sentral.
People started queuing up for the train at 2000.
<img src="/assets/kb_trip/jb-queue.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>Train started the journey at 2030 to the dot.
Train coaches were clean and comfortable.
<img src="/assets/kb_trip/train-inside.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>It also had a café coach with hot drinks and food.
<img src="/assets/kb_trip/train-caffe.jpg" alt="wide" /></p>
<p>The most of the train trip is through the night, and I unknowingly booked backward seats which didn't make the trip any easier.
There were sleeping coaches in the train, but tickets all sold out at the time of booking (a week before).
If I'm going to make this trip again, I'll definitely book a bed in a sleeping coach.</p>
<p>Sun was up when the train was reaching Gua Musang.
<img src="/assets/kb_trip/gua-musang.jpg" alt="" />
The train through its route via central and east sides of Malaysia runs through mostly rural areas with lots of palm cultivation and occasional patches of jungle.
<img src="/assets/kb_trip/return-scene1.jpg" alt="wide" /></p>
<p><img src="/assets/kb_trip/return-scene2.jpg" alt="wide" /></p>
<p><img src="/assets/kb_trip/scene3.jpg" alt="wide" /></p>
<p>We also crossed few of muddy rivers.
<img src="/assets/kb_trip/muddy-river.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>And few big cities.
<img src="/assets/kb_trip/town.jpg" alt="wide" /></p>
<p>Train stations were big and looked new.
And It's possible to see the old stations beside few new stations.
The train was fully air-conditioned and freezing at the night.
<img src="/assets/kb_trip/freezing.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>We got off from Wakaf Baru, the nearest station to Kota Baru (KB) around 1230 on Friday
<img src="/assets/kb_trip/train.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>KB is 10 min taxi ride away from Wakaf Baru.
And it's the capitol of Kelantan state and the biggest city in northeast Malaysia.
State of Kelantan is known for woodwork and batik painting, which we got to know from few museum visits on the following day.</p>
<p>Once off from the train we took a taxi to the place of our stay, which is through the KB city and about 10kmm away from the train station.
It's a bit hard to find the place at first.
But once found, the place was nice enough.</p>
<p>After taking a shower and resting for a while we took another taxi to the Aeon shopping mall.
Which is the biggest in the KB city.
<img src="/assets/kb_trip/aeon-mall.jpg" alt="" />
The train ride was taxing more than expected.
So we're not in the mood for any adventures.</p>
<p>On the way we saw lots of mosques.
<img src="/assets/kb_trip/mosque.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>When in Malaysia, I feel most comfortable when I'm in a shopping mall.
Most probably there similarity to the malls in Singapore.
The mall we visited was huge and looked new.
We walked around the mall and had lunch/dinner at Nandos.
Then took a taxi back home.</p>
<p>Following day (Saturday) we visited following.</p>
<ul>
<li>Central market</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/assets/kb_trip/central-market.jpg" alt="wide" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Two Museums (I forgot the names)</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/assets/kb_trip/museum.jpg" alt="wide" /></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Handcraft Village</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Batik painting place - and painted a batik</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/assets/kb_trip/batik.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>KB Mall</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Street Art Place</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/assets/kb_trip/street-art.jpg" alt="wide" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Night Market</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/assets/kb_trip/nightmarket.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>Then we took a taxi back home.</p>
<p>For the Sunday we're planning to visit a beach and a Thai temple before taking the train back home.
We started with the beach.
Which was quite nice.
<img src="/assets/kb_trip/pcb-beach.jpg" alt="wide" />
And we had an interesting lunch near the beach.
<img src="/assets/kb_trip/pcb-lunch1.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p><img src="/assets/kb_trip/pcb-beach-lunch-coconut.jpg" alt="" />
But we ran in to trouble finding taxi back home.
It took an hour to book a taxi.
This experience discouraged us going to the Thai temple.
Because it's also a bit far from the city, and we were in tight schedule to catch the train.</p>
<p>So instead of going to the temple we went back to the Aeon shopping mall.
And chilled there for few hours before going to train station to catch the train.
<img src="/assets/kb_trip/WB-return.jpg" alt="" />
This train starts from Tumpat at 2030 and reached the Wakaf Baru at 2045.
Train was on time though out the whole journey.</p>
<p>Return trip was quite similar to the first trip.
But this time we managed to book seats facing forward.
(And we got a 50% refund for the original return ticket).
<img src="/assets/kb_trip/train-line-window.jpg" alt="" />
Also, we managed to sleep in the train more than we did on first trip.</p>
<p>Once we reached the JB Sentral it was around 1230.
Our next leg of the journey is a train shuttle from JB Sentral to Singapore at 1400.
We had a quick tea before queuing up for the shuttle.</p>
<p>The whole trip costed ~140 SGD including train tickets (MYR 43 one way per pax).</p>
<p>To be honest, though the trip is quite good, the best part of it is coming back home.</p>
<p>More photos, <a href="/photos/Kota-Bharu/" target="_blank">photos/Kota-Bharu</a>.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Walk in the Park(s)</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-07-08-Walk-in-the-Park(s)/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>It all started with an article on Straight Times Singapore.
The Story is about group of people walking from Raffles Marina lighthouse in Singapore to Inscription of island in Changi.
Total distance was 60+ km.
I asked few of my friend from SMU if they are interested to do such walk.
Eight of them were.</p>
<p>We planned to do the walk on 6th of July 2024.
Meet up point is Tuas-Link MRT at 8pm.
I drew the <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/d/edit?mid=1t72893BO0iOoIDPzb3DhYpAIa7SEuyQ&usp=sharing" target="_blank">route for the walk</a> and shared with the group.</p>
<p>On the walk day, I got a sore throat.
Did a covid test which reported negative.
To be hones I think I'll be happier if it came positive.
Because I'm not feeling very well.
But since I'm the organizer of the walk, I need a good excuse if I'm to skip the walk.
And just &quot;not feeling well&quot; isn't going to cut it.</p>
<p>We met at Tuas Link MRT as planned.
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/tuas-mrt.jpg" alt="" />
There were six of us at the beginning.
Three of the original party didn't show up, but we got a new member.</p>
<p>We walked up to the Raffles Marina lighthouse to start the walk.
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/raffles-lighthouse.jpg" alt="" />
First leg of the walk is through the Tuas area.
The industrial area of Singapore.
Roads were wide and deserted at the early night.
First stretch is from Raffles Marina lighthouse to Ulu Pandan reservoir.
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/ulu-pandan.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>One of the group dropped from the walk after first stretch.
We restocked our water and went for a nearby food stall for a tea.
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/football-cafe.jpg" alt="" />
After the tea went to a Fair price to buy some snacks.
Two more of our group dropped from the walk, and opted to cycle to home after the Fair Price.</p>
<p>Second leg of the walk is through the PCN to Buono Vista.
We were three to begin the second leg.
PCN is almost deserted, but it's much better walking experience compared to the first leg.
When we reached Bonavista we've walked total of 25km.</p>
<p>At Bonavista, remaining two members also decided to end the walk.
And I started the third leg of the walk to ECP alone.
This part is also quite similar to the second leg.
It's all through the PCN up until ECP.</p>
<p>When I reached the Robertson Quay it's early morning of Sunday.
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/clarke.jpg" alt="" />
From Robertson Quay to Clarke Quay there were few people trying to postpone a hangover.
And there were lighted up bridges.
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/red-bridge.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>Flier looked beautiful from the bridge crossing Singapore river.
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/flier.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>At the beginning of ECP it's still dark.
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/ecp-start.jpg" alt="" />
But by the time I reach the Food Village there was some light.
And few shops were open including my favorite Popiah place.
For the breakfast I had two Popiah and a tea (which was too sweet).
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/popiah.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>Then I started the fourth leg of my walk from ECP to Changi Loop.
By then it's a bright morning painted with a light drizzle.
Lots of people taking their weekly outdoor dose at the park.
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/ecp.jpg" alt="" />
I feel out of the whole route this part is the most pleasant.</p>
<p>At the beginning of Changi loop there was a choice.
Either to continue via Changi loop or cut through the city to Changi beach.
And I chose to go via Changi loop.
Which I regretted around 1/3 in to the loop.
There were no people, and it's literary a desert (with trees).
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/changi-loop.jpg" alt="" />
Whole loop was about 20km.
And I had to do it alone.
There wasn't even place to sit.</p>
<p>It's quite hard to explain how I felt during that part.
I think it's like person stuck on a lonely island who's forced to walk.
I tried singing aloud but had a hard time remembering any lyrics.
So I focused on completing the walk as fast as possible, and tried to keep the pace at 10min/km (mine usual is ~11min/km).
It was a good distraction.</p>
<p>At the end of Changi loop is Changi park connector.
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/changi-beach-connector.jpg" alt="" />
And there was water refiling station near the &quot;Changi tree&quot;.
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/changi-tree.jpg" alt="" />
Sun was up by now, and I was exhausted.
Only the idea of finishing the walk kept me going at this point.</p>
<p>Right after the Changi tree it's Changi point.
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/changi-point-pano.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Once I reached the Changi Beach Park I was almost crawling.
I went to the Inscription and took a photo to mark the end.
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/inscription.jpg" alt="" />
My watch said I walked total of 69.76 km in total of 16 hours and 51 minutes.
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/finish-watch.jpg" alt="" />
I spent about 15 min there in the park resting the legs, and went to Changi Village hawker center to get lunch.
<img src="/assets/blog/walk/lunch.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>Then took a long hard ride to a hot bath.</p>
<p><a href="https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/16281484174" target="_blank">Link to activity in Garmin Connect</a></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>0615 Run</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-06-28-0615-Run/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Last month I signed up for Singapore Marathon.
Then I bought a heart-rate strap.
Searched for a marathon training program and found one.
But couldn't find a time to run.
My evenings have found a way to be occupied someway or other.
So thought of doing a morning run.</p>
<p>By now I'm quite familiar about the problem of different person waking up than the one went asleep.
So me and my flatmate, (he's also into running) we came to an agreement.
If either of us didn't show up at 0615 all set to run, will have to buy wok-hey for the other.</p>
<p>And it worked.
Today we did a morning run.
And ran for about 3 km.
I felt quite out of breath during the run.
Either I'm out of shape or I didn't find the rhythm today.</p>
<p>The weather was nice today though.
And got to a great start for the day.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/blog/0615-run.jpg" alt="" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Home Trip</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-05-30-Home-Trip/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I was home for almost two weeks now.
I came here on 17th this month and will be going back this Sunday.
Up to now it rained every day to varying degrees.</p>
<p>Traveling in Sri Lanka on public transport in not an easy job.
It's crowded and unpredictable.
When it rains the difficulty to travel multiplies.</p>
<p>So most of these two weeks were spent at home.
I had to scrap few plans to meet friends.
It's very hard to leave a cozy home when raining outside and road is muddy.</p>
<p>But I managed to make few trips and shoot some photos even it rained,</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://kasungamlath.com/photos/Lake-Round-Kurunegala-On-A-Rainy-Day/">Kurunegala</a></li>
<li><a href="https://kasungamlath.com/photos/Well-of-Death/">Wattarama</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Few backyard photo session,</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://kasungamlath.com/photos/Chili,-Flower,-and-a-Dog/">Session 1</a></li>
<li><a href="https://kasungamlath.com/photos/Back-Yard-Nature-Photography/">Session 2</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Add few books to my book list,</p>
<ul>
<li>Valley of the Dolls <em>by Jacqueline Susann</em></li>
<li>The Outsider <em>by Stephen King</em></li>
</ul>
<p>And watch numerous movies !!!</p>
<p>At the end it became a very relaxing (and kind of boring) vacation at home.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Color Green</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-05-30-Color-Green/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p><img src="/assets/blog/green.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Human eyes are most sensitive to color green.
The light rays of color green activates 2 out of 3 color receptors of the eyes.</p>
<p>In the ancient times when humans are surrounded with green it helped them source food and identify danger.
Color green also helps human to calm down.
The Tranquil quality of the green explains the green paintings on hospital walls.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bachata</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-04-30-Bachata/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>After much deliberation, last February I started going to bachata classes.
So far I completed ~10 classes.
As someone who has no ear for music, it's quite a hard to learn.</p>
<p>In bachata, guys usually lead the dance.
So they need to find the beat and get the ball rolling, so to speak.
Even after 10 classes I still struggle to find the beat, and then to get the count correct.</p>
<p>With no muscle memory to help, I feel my brain working at maximum to coordinate the difference aspects of the dance.
And I feel the brain fuming after about an hour.</p>
<p>I guess this will be much easier with any kind of prior dancing experience, or with a ear for music.
So far it's an interesting, and humbling experience for me.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>End of Second Term</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-04-21-End-of-Second-Term/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Past week was the first exam week (exams usually held over two weeks) for the second term of 23-24 academic year.
Exams for both of the courses I was supporting, and the course I was reading for the masters, held during last week.
So (except for few grading components) term is over for me.</p>
<p>Time to enjoy the summer break.</p>
<p>This second term felt harder than the first term.
May be because I was supporting two new courses.
Or because initial enthusiasm for the new job is over.
But I felt I did much better compared to the first term.
Both at supporting the courses and reading for the masters course.</p>
<p>For the record I was supporting CS205-Operating Systems with Android and IS113-Web Application development 1.
And I was reading the CS704-Information Systems.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Taming the Day v2</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-03-27-Taming-the-Day-v2/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<ul>
<li>Wake-up: 0630</li>
<li>Prep: 0630 - 0730</li>
<li>Morning: 0730 - 1130</li>
<li>Break 1: 1130 - 1300</li>
<li>Afternoon: 1300 - 1500</li>
<li>Break 2: 1500 - 1530</li>
<li>Evening: 1530 - 1730</li>
<li>Plan the next day: 1730 - 1800</li>
<li>Void: 1800 - 2200</li>
<li>Sleep: 2200</li>
</ul>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Taming the Day v1</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-03-26-Taming-the-Day-v1/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<ul>
<li>wake-up: 0630</li>
<li>prep: 0630 - 0730</li>
<li>first part: 0730 - 1130</li>
<li>break: 1130 - 1330</li>
<li>second part: 1330 - 1730</li>
<li>plan the next day: 1730 - 1800</li>
<li>void: 1800 - 2200</li>
<li>sleep: 2200</li>
</ul>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Challah Bread</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-03-19-Challah-Bread/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Early this month I made Challah bread (for the first time).
Following are the ingredients and process recommended by (my baking instructor) TOM.</p>
<h3>Ingredients</h3>
<ul>
<li>wheat Floor - 300g</li>
<li>water - 150g</li>
<li>sugar - 30g</li>
<li>yeast - 6g</li>
<li>salt - to taste</li>
<li>honey - 1 tea spoon</li>
</ul>
<h3>Process</h3>
<ol>
<li>Mix all the ingreadients together. Knead it. Leave it for ~2 hours.</li>
<li>Knead the mixture again. Leave it for ~30 min.</li>
<li>Make the structure of bread.</li>
<li>Leave it for ~30 min.</li>
</ol>
<p>Mine looked like this.
<img src="/assets/bread/before.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<ol start="5">
<li>Preheat the oven to 180C.</li>
<li>Bake the bread for ~25 min.</li>
<li>Take the bread out and let it cool in room tempreture.</li>
</ol>
<p>Final result looked like this.
<img src="/assets/bread/after.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Apart from having not enough salt, It tasted like bread.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Second Midterm</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2024-02-18-Second-Midterm/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Next week is going to be the midterm of my second term.
On teaching and reading for the masters.
I feel like this term is more work heavy than the last.
But past always looks easy, compared to the present.
(And future harder.)
Next week I got to do a lab, and sit for a midterm exam on the same day.</p>
<p>Didn't play beach tennis this weekend since my right arm is still sour in the mornings.
Due to playing badminton with wrong technique.
Think it needs more resting.
And my bike badly needs an overhauling.</p>
<p>This morning I went to the library and spend most productive 3 hours I can remember.
I should do it more often.
Only at the library I realized how hard it is to concentrate on the office.</p>
<p>Working is like riding a bike.
You pick up the speed and find the rhythm.
Then somebody comes up to you, and you run in to a red light.
After that need to redo the speeding up part.
That's hard.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Trip to Malaysia</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-12-19-Trip-to-Malaysia/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Last weekend I went to Malaysia for a 2 day trip.
This marks the third country I've being to, so far.
I visited Johor Bahru (JB).
JB happends to be a popular weekend-gateway for people in Singapore.
It's the closest to singapore (and can be visited by land)</p>
<p>I took a bus to JB.
The bus is operated by SMRT and starts from woodlands terminal.
Bus goes straight to the woodlands checkpoint.
Alighted at the checkpoint and went through the emigration process from singapore.
After that took another bus to the JB checkpoint.
At JB checkpoint alighted again and went through the Malaysian immigration.
Then took a cab to Pelangi Plaza to have lunch.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/jb_trip_2023/lunch.jpeg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Pelangi Plaza shopping mall looks desserted except for only a few visitors.
Food prices were quit cheaper compared to Singapore.
While having the lunch booked a nearby hotel to stay.</p>
<p>After the lunch started walking to the hotel (following the postal code).</p>
<p><img src="/assets/jb_trip_2023/walking.jpeg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Followed the postal code turned out to be a mistake.
Though in singapore the area covered by one postal code is very small,
Malaysia it's huge.
After about 2km walk stoped for a milkshake and check of the map.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/jb_trip_2023/tea1.jpeg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Turnes out hotel is already passed while walking.</p>
<p>Discovering that, took a cab to the hotel (cab fares are also cheaper than singapore).
Then rested for a while and went to KSL mall for bit of a shopping and the dinner.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/jb_trip_2023/fried-rice.jpeg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Follwing the dinner walked back to the hotel.</p>
<p>Following morning went to look for a place to have the breakfast.
And found a nice nearby place.</p>
<table width="100%"><tr>
<td width="33%"> <img src="/assets/jb_trip_2023/tea2.jpeg" alt="Drawing"/> </td>
<td width="33%"> <img src="/assets/jb_trip_2023/roti.jpeg" alt="Drawing"/> </td>
<td width="33%"> <img src="/assets/jb_trip_2023/chicken.jpeg" alt="Drawing"/> </td>
</tr></table>
<p>The breakfast turned out to be quite nice.
After the breakfast came back to hotel, checked out and went to Holiday Plaza.
There did bit of more shopping and had another tea with fried banana.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/jb_trip_2023/tea3.jpeg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>After that went to Johor Bahru City Square which is next to the JB emigration.
Following bit of further shopping there, went through the emigration process and came back to Singapore.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Photo Book 2023</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-12-13-Photo-Book-2023/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Designing a photo book was one of my goals for this year.
My first thought was to design a book with about 20 pages.
With one photo per page.
But after choosing the photos, I ended up with 50 pages book.</p>
<p>To design the book, I settled on Affinity Publisher.
They have a 30 days free trial.</p>
<p><a href="/assets/photobook2023.pdf">link to the final e-version (~120MB)</a></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>SCSM 2023 My First Full Marathon</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-12-04-SCSM-2023-My-First-Full-Marathon/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>After finishing 3 half-marathons over past few years, yesterday I did my first full marathon.
And it took 6 hours and 22 minutes for me to finish.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/scsm2023-stats.png" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>I finished the first half in 2:30.
But after that my legs started complaining.
So had to walk for the most of the second part.
I was afraid, else I won't be able to finish the race.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/scsm2023-splits.png" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>It was a great experience.
Felt like I have grown into big boy pants running a full-marathon after 3 half-marathons.
But last year half-marathon was more fun (except for the raining at the beginning).
Mostly because it's my first in-person half-marathon, and I did run all the way.
I find running is far more enjoyable than walking in a race.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/scsm2023-time-distribution.png" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Full distribution of completion time for all the finishers.
Highlighted is my time.</p>
<p>And few more bonus plots on SCSM 2023.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/scsm2023-age-groups-num-of-runners.png" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p><img src="/assets/scsm2023-age-groups-finish-time.png" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p><a href="/assets/scsm2023.csv">link to csv file</a></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>SCSM 2023 Day Before Race</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-12-02-SCSM-2023-Day-Before-Race/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Today is the day before Standard Charted Singapore Marathon 2023.
Which is going to be my first marathon.
And I hope, it won’t rain at the beginning like at the last half-marathon.</p>
<p>My target this time is to just finish the marathon.
Cut off time is 8:30 hours.
And my last year half-marathon was 2:20.
So I think it should be OK.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>End of Term One</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-11-23-End-of-Term-One/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>This week is the 1st (out of 2) exam week for the term 1 of my masters (and my Instructor career) at SMU.
I only read one course for the master, and it didn’t have final exam.
So 1st term of my masters is officially done.
For the Instructing, I still have to invigilate two exams.
After that instructor work for 1st term is done.
Then I get to prep for the term two.</p>
<p>All in all term one was great.
Getting used to studying and teaching at the same time was novel to say the least.</p>
<p>Teaching is fun.
Hardest thing I found about the teaching is keeping the students’ attention throughout the class.
If the lesson is too easy I loose the half of the class.
If too challenging I loose other half of the class.
Finding the balance is a trick.
And each section (set of students) is different.
So need to be able to read the class well, in order to be a good instructor.</p>
<p>Reading for the masters was also a pleasant experience.
Except for the lecture timing.
It’s very hard to focus during 7pm-10pm, specially given I started the day at 6am.
But the personal interest I had for the course I took (Deep Learning and Computer vision was interesting) made it bearable.
I finally get to learn the theory behind some of the stuff I worked on for past couple of years.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Back to School as a student</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-08-24-Back-to-School-as-a-student/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>This month I started reading for my masters.
My program requires me covering six courses (6 CU) plus one capstone project (4 CU) over the span of next 2-3 years.
I decided to take only one module for this term, because</p>
<ol>
<li>It’s being a long time I’ve being a student in a class room.</li>
<li>I just did a major career change (from engineer to teacher) and still getting used to the new role.</li>
<li>The other module I wanted to take is on Thursday (1900-2215) and I have to teach two sections on Thursday (0800-1100 &amp; 1200-1500). On top of that I’ll be teaching another section on Friday morning at 0800.</li>
</ol>
<p>The course I’m taking is CS701 - computer vision and deep learning, which I already have some practical experience.</p>
<p>The worst thing about the lecture is timing.<br />
1900-2215 is definitely not a good time to be sitting in a lecture.
But it cannot be helped.</p>
<p>All in all it’s fun to be back in school.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>New Career</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-08-24-New-Career/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>This is the second week of my 3rd career.
After graduating, in 2016 February I started my career as a software engineer.
In 2018 Aug I started working as a research engineer.
After 5 years now in 2023 Aug I am a teacher. Instructor to be exact.</p>
<p>I feel research engineer to instructor transition is more drastic than the transition from software engineer to research engineer.
Now I have to keep regular office hours (at least on the days I’m teaching).
Also once the week finishes work for that week is also finishes, unlike in engineering where tasks get carried over for long time and never really finishes.</p>
<p>This term I’m supporting four sections of a first year course.
Three sections from 0815-1115, and one from 1530-1830 which spans over three days.</p>
<p>This forces me to wake up early.
And I figured out waking up early everyday is much easier than waking up early only on some of the days.
(Finally I’m working on my new year resolution).</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Instagram Captions</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-07-08-Instagram-Captions/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I have changed the IG Helpers name to Instagram Captions because IH Helper acronym-IGH sounds like an hospital.
Now the acronym stands as IGC, which sounds like something related to cricket.
Anyways it's going to be IGC until I come up with a good name.</p>
<p>Apart from that I've given it a facelift with bootstrap.
And few tweaks to the backend.</p>
<p>It's now hosted at <a href="http://igc.kasungamlath.com">igc.kasungamlath.com</a></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>IG Helper public release</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-05-25-IG-Helper-public-release/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p><video controls><source src="/assets/blog/igh-public-1.mp4" type="video/mp4">Your browser does not support the video tag.</video></p>
<h3>change log</h3>
<h4>frontend</h4>
<ul>
<li>hosted on AWS s3 -&gt; <a href="http://igh-frontend.s3-website-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/">link</a></li>
<li>new favicon</li>
<li>disabled auto loading descriptions</li>
<li>add button to request descriptions</li>
<li>made description clickable</li>
</ul>
<h4>backend</h4>
<ul>
<li>hosted on AWS beanstalk (EC2 + RDS )</li>
<li>increased the db descriptions column max length to 1024 - fixed issue descriptions not returning for some images</li>
</ul>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Instagram Helper Teaser</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-05-20-Instagram-Helper-Teaser/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>“Never spend 6 minutes doing something by hand when you can spend 6 hours failing to automate it” -quote</p>
<p><video controls><source src="/assets/blog/igh-teaser.mp4" type="video/mp4">Your browser does not support the video tag.</video></p>
<p>But I didn’t fail, though it took way more than 6 hours.
And as a friend pointed out, I'll break even someday (if I keep using it).</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>GRE and IELTS</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-04-02-GRE-and-IELTS/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I took the GRE and IELTS last month and got the results yesterday. I prepared for the GRE for about 2 weeks and IELTS for about 5 days. That was just enough to get used to the exam style. And get the mind ready for tests. It's roughly a walk in. I did it not because I was confident but because time was running out for me.</p>
<p>For GRE I scored 306/340 total with 155/170 for quant section. My target was 310 total as for the results I got for the sample tests. Minimum score one can get is 260 total for the GRE test. For context top tier universities ask for 320+ total score when considering students. But 300+ score is considered decent.</p>
<p>Out of the two GRE is obviously harder. The hardest part for me was to stay focused throughout the test. It was a 3+ hour continuous test. And my brain was fuming towards the end. I think the reason is not enough preparation. I was not ready for a 3+ hour test. I only did 2 mock tests provided with registering. If I'm to do it again I'll buy more sample tests and spend time doing them. And I think next time it's better to spend at least about 2 months preparing for the test.</p>
<p>For the IELTS I got a 7/9 overall score. My target score was the same. The Maximum score I got is for Reading, 8/9. Most probably a result of my reading habit. Lowest is for writing, 6/9. I thought my writings were better. But it seems it's not. Anyways it's not up to the standards of IELTS. And I should now work on more to improve my writing skills, because I think it's an important skill. So expect more quality blog posts here.</p>
<p>In hindsight, For IELTS preparation I should have spent about a month. And I should've worked more on the writing section and speaking. I didn't practice speaking at all. As practice I think just speaking more and learning and using new words is the important thing. And observing how other people talk.</p>
<p>Well for my next target these scores seem enough. So I won't be taking these tests any time soon. And I'm happy with the decision to do them even in a hurry.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Canon RF 2470mm f2</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-03-09-Canon-RF-2470mm-f2/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>This week I bought my 2nd lens of the holy trinity.
24-70mm f2.8.
I already had the 70-200mm f2.8 lens.</p>
<p>I was looking for a clear sky to take some nature pics.
Which still not arrived.
But I did some experiments with product photography.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/product-photography.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>Something I read while back keep popping in to the mind.
“Fearing the fear.”
This week I “discovered” Singapore National Library Building at Bugis.
And It’s real nice to place to do focused work.</p>
<p>I also noted I skipped writing blog posts for past 2 weeks.
(Right after the self proclamation to write a post once every week)
Well it’s better late than never.
I’ll be posting 2 back dated posts along with this post.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>BBQ in ECP</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-03-05-BBQ-in-ECP/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>My fever has gone down.
Leaving the memory of a groggy weekend.
It felt like I lived the last weekend through a mist.
The appetite is not back yet.
So far I lost about 2kg.</p>
<p>Last Monday I received 3 bad news.
One being doctor’s assessment that I might have dengue.
But that dengue is shot lived.
By Tuesday I got the negative blood test results.</p>
<p>All in it’s an uneventful week.</p>
<p>On Saturday I went to a BBQ in ECP.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/bbq3.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sick Weekend</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-02-25-Sick-Weekend/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I went to the gym for 3 days skipping Wednesday.
Then got a fever on Thursday.
I thought it’s from too much of gym.
But seems I also lost my appetite.
So it must be something I ate.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>2023 So Far</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-02-19-2023-So-Far/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>January was all rain.
That means no cycling, no Tennis, only an occasional run.</p>
<p>Office work is also in a challenging mode.
Because, for the Neuromorphic project we recently started, I needed to learn low level details on deep learning.</p>
<p>But my gym frequency is good so far.
I've made a New-Year resolution to go to gym at 9am, 4 days per week.
After a rough start, that habit is settiling in now.
Last week I started doing Jim Wendler's 5/3/1 BB program properly.</p>
<p>I did,</p>
<ul>
<li>bench press - 30 x 5, 35 x 5, 40 x 5, 30 x 10 x 5</li>
<li>back squat - 45 x 5, 50 x 5, 55 x 5, 40 x 10 x 5</li>
<li>dead lift - 60 x 5, 70 x 5, 85 x 5, 50 x 10 x 5</li>
<li>overhead press - 20 x 5, 25 x 5, 30 x 5, 20 x 10 x 5</li>
</ul>
<p>For whatever reason squats hit me the hardest and I had trouble climbing stairs even after 2 days of work out.</p>
<p>There were 2 BBQ nights back to back on last 2 saturdays.
Come to think of it, one in East (of singapore) and other in West.</p>
<p>I also did my friend's post-wedding shoot last week.
Photos turned out to be quite OK considering I had to use the sony a6000 with kit lens.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Writing a Blog Post per Week</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2023-02-18-Writing-a-Blog-Post-per-Week/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Writing blog posts is hard.
Writing blog posts consistently is harder.</p>
<p>I haven't wrote one in about 7 weeks now.
And this is a self proclamation that I'll be writing a blog post at least per week from now on.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cycling Around Singapore 3rd Attempt</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2022-12-30-Cycling-Around-Singapore-3rd-Attempt/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Third time is a charm.
After two failed attempts,
today I managed to complete the round island cycle ride.
Granted I lost the track few times and ended up in highways 2 times,
I finished 120km ride in 9:30 hours.
And did it solo.</p>
<p>I started around 10pm on Dec29th.
I dined at Macdonalds in ECP around 1am(Hawker center was closed)
Caught in a little drizzle around 4am
Otherwise whether was perfect.
Then had morning tea at Kranji at 5.30 am.
Last 20km was the hardest.
The traffic was also dense after 6am.
Finished before 8am on Den 30th.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/cycle_around_sg_3.png" alt="full-width" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>SCSM 2022 Race Day</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2022-12-04-SCSM-2022-Race-Day/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>There were thunderstorms at 4.30am.
Time the race supposed to start.
Race was delayed until 5.30am.
20,000 people waited for an hour in the rain anxious to start running.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/half-marathon-2022-people.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Running in-person race feels physically hard but mentally easy.
Physically hard because you're surrounded by other runners,
had to run around them some times and try to avoid tripping.
Mentally easy because again you're surrounded by other runners.
And there were people cheering.
Cheering with funny slogans.</p>
<ul>
<li>&quot;You could've played chess&quot;</li>
<li>&quot;I'm sure it seemed a good idea 4 months ago&quot;</li>
</ul>
<p>At the end it's a great experience,
even though it's a dripping start.
According to my 1 year old Garmin data I made 4 personal records in today's race.</p>
<ol>
<li>Fasted 5k - 27:56</li>
<li>Fastest 10k - 59:37</li>
<li>Fastest half marathon - 2:14:04</li>
<li>Longest run - 21.93km</li>
</ol>
<p>But again Garmin map was a mess, because the route was through the high rise buildings.
According to SCSM numbers, my Net time was 02:21:11 with 02:33:48 gun time.
So the official timing for the half marathon in 02:21:11.
30 minutes less than last year.
6+ minutes bellow my target.
But given the bad start it's a good time IMO.
Thank you Garmin coach.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/half-marathon-2022-full-time.png" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Hardest part of the route was the arc shaped bridge around 18km mark.
Running through the climb made me breathless.
And it took sometime to recover back.
But I managed to make my last leg the fastest.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/half-marathon-2022-split-time.png" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Until next year.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>SCSM 2022 Day Before Race</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2022-12-03-SCSM-2022-Day-Before-Race/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Just few more hours to the race.
My first in-person half marathon.
I want to run it in less than 2 hours and 15 minutes.
My last year (virtual) half marathon took 2 hours and 50 minutes.</p>
<p>I would rather prefer if the race started early night,
instead early morning.
But Nothing to do about it.
Flag off is at 4.30am.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/2022_half_marathon-training.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Flying Home</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2022-09-29-Flying-Home/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I never liked flying.
I hate the waiting until the flight.
Flying itself is not so bad.
Once I get in to the plane, It's all good.
I just don't like the waiting.</p>
<p>This is the second time this year I'm flying.
First time was more interesting.
First time this year was the first time I flew since covid.
After about a 2 years wait.</p>
<p>I think it gets little better each time.
Meaning if I fly more frequently I'll feel better.
But the issue is I'm also not very keen on flying.</p>
<p>Travel by train - well that's a way of traveling I like.
Issue with flying is, there's nothing to the journey.
There's no scenery.
You hop on a plane and try to kill the time until you get off.
And the hassle of checking in and out.</p>
<p>Granted - It's (unfortunately) the fastest way to travel.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Haar cascade Detection for License Plates with OpenCV</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2022-09-23-Haar-cascade-Detection-for-License-Plates-with-OpenCV/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Recently I needed to detect license plates in a power efficient way.
Object detection using Haar feature based cascade classifiers,
is proposed by Paul Viola and Michael Jones in there paper &quot;Rapid Object Detection using a Boosted Cascade of Simple Features&quot; in 2001.
It's a power efficient machine learning model.</p>
<p>Training Haar feature based model involve bunch of positive images (in our case images with license plates) and negative images (images without license plates).
<a href="https://docs.opencv.org/3.4/dc/d88/tutorial_traincascade.html">here</a> is nice tutorial on training the model.</p>
<p>For our case we didn't need to train a model.
OpenCV comes with few already trained <a href="https://github.com/opencv/opencv/tree/master/data/haarcascades">models</a>.
Two of them are for detecting number plates.
I tried both of them on our dataset and chose the best performing one.
It managed to detect about 10-15% of license plates on our <a href="https://github.com/kpgx/benchmarks/tree/master/endtoend/us">dataset</a>.</p>
<p>Sample images - both positive and negative detections,</p>
<p><img src="/assets/haar/car0.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p><img src="/assets/haar/car1.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p><img src="/assets/haar/car2.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p><img src="/assets/haar/car3.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p><img src="/assets/haar/car4.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p><img src="/assets/haar/car5.jpg" alt="" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Training for the 3rd Half Marathon</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2022-09-22-Training-for-the-3rd-Half-Marathon/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I'm planning to run my 3rd half marathon this December.
This is the third time and it's a &quot;real&quot;/in-person race.
Last two times were virtual because of COVID restrictions.
This is my second in-person race and I'm quite excited.</p>
<p>Since both of previous half marathons took almost 3 hours,
This time I thought of following a structured training to improve the timing.
I signed up for Garmin Coach half marathon training program with a two hour time goal.
It's a 15 week program with 4 days training per week.
Now I'm on the 5th week.
At the moment Garmin Coach it pretty confidence that I can meet the time goal.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/garmin_coach.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>But there's a planned upset in my training.
I'll be away from running for a month due to my travelling.
So I'm not quite sure how it'll impact my training.
If it impacts it'll be in a bad way.
Nevertheless I'm following the plan and going to run on this December.
Hopefully meeting the time goal.</p>
<p>BTW I paused my GYM program until the race to make time for running.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Measuring Energy Usage on Jetson Products</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2022-09-17-Measuring-Energy-Usage-on-Jetson-Products/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Recently we finalized a project which involved running Machine Learning on a edge device.
For edge devices we chose jetson nano and jetson tx2.
Big part of our project was about the power usage on running ML on edge devices.
To achieve this we needed to measure the power usage of our edge devices.</p>
<p>Now Jetson boards come with sensors (in there boards) to calculate the energy usage.
So it's not a &quot;must&quot; requirement use external power measuring devices (as with RPI devices).
There's a handy tool named <a href="https://developer.nvidia.com/docs/drive/drive-os/latest/linux/sdk/common/topics/util_setup/tegrastatsUtility1.html">tegrastats</a> which can be used to read the power sensor values.
How tegrastats work is once it's invoked, it prints the sensor readings periodically.
So it's possible to redirect it's output to a file and later parse it to get the required values.</p>
<p>Another way of gathering power readings is using one of nice tool built around tegrastats.
Like <a href="https://github.com/rbonghi/jetson_stats">jtop</a> (jetson_stats)
It's written in python.
Jtop looks much like htop but with additional power values.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/jtop.gif" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>It also come with an easy to use script that logs the sensor readings.
Thus parsing the jtop output is easier compared to tegrastats output.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>My Next Camera Setup</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2022-09-05-My-Next-Camera-Setup/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I bought my sony alpha a6000 camera with 16-50mm kit lens 3+ years ago.
Later I added 55-210mm kit lens.
Then 35mm f/1.8 prime.
And I was using the camera at least once per week.</p>
<p>Recently I started to feel like I've grown out of my lens setup.
Now I'm sure I want to make photography a serious hobby.
So started thinking about a lens upgrade.</p>
<p>My initial plan was to replace the two kit lenses with high-ends.
But it occured to me that, not so far down the road the cropped sensor might become the limiting factor.
And I'll end up with needing to replace whole setup for a full frame system.
So why not start building the full frame system now ?</p>
<p>Granted the initial expense is high.
But assuming a pro lenses can easily last 10+ years and don't loose much value with time,
In the long run it's a OK expense.
If I shoot once a week initial expense will be devided by 10x52 = 520 per one shooting session.
Assuming 10k initial expense, per session becomes ~20 SGD.</p>
<p>After making sure the math is correct,
I started researching on Full Frame cameras.
And it seems (at the moment) Cannon make the best full frame mirrorless lenses.
Though collection of lenses is limted compared to Sony available lenses were better.</p>
<p>So I bought the Canon R6 (680g with battery + SD card) with 70-200mm f/2.8 (1200g with tripod mount).
lens really fast, sharp and whole setup (at 1880g) is quite OK to carry.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Gym Progress after 3 Months</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2022-08-29-Gym-Progress-after-3-Months/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>It's being 3 months and 1 week since I started going to gym.
For the first 2 months I followed reddit's beginer program for lifters.
Then I moved to Jim Wendler's 5/3/1 program.
First tried it for 4 days / week.
But found it's too much.
Then moved to 2 days / week.</p>
<p>My Curren status of lifting is,</p>
<ul>
<li>Bench Press - 35x5, 40x5, 45x5, 35x8x4</li>
<li>Back Squats - 50x5, 55x5, 60x5, 45x10x5</li>
<li>Deadlift - 50x5, 55x5, 60x5, 40x10x5</li>
<li>Overhead Press - 17.5x5, 20x5 25x5, 15x10x5</li>
</ul>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>New Place</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2022-05-26-New-Place/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>It's being 25 days since I moved to the new place.
So far It's all good.</p>
<p>New place has 2 big(50m) pools and few small ones.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/new-place/pool.jpeg" alt="full-width" />
^View of pool from the balcony.</p>
<p>I've being trying to improve my swimming(freestyle) technique.
I can swim 50m at one go.
But then need to rest.
I think my technique is quite bad to say the least.
For example my head usually above the water when swimming.</p>
<p>I bought a small projector(Wanbo T2 Max).</p>
<p><img src="/assets/new-place/projector.jpeg" alt="full-width" />
^How it looks when laying in bed.</p>
<p>Now it's closer to my work place.
My commute time is reduced to ~25min from ~45min.</p>
<p>And it's close to East Coast Park(ECP).
20min bike ride.
I believe I've being to the ECP almost every weekend.
Which is quite fun.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/new-place/ecp.jpeg" alt="full-width" />
^People playing beach tennis in ECP.</p>
<p>And there're lot's of good eating places around.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/new-place/wanton_noodle.jpeg" alt="full-width" />
^Wanton noodle.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/new-place/mysore_mutton_biriyani.jpeg" alt="full-width" />
^Mysore mutton biriyani.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/new-place/fish_fillet.jpeg" alt="full-width" />
^Grilled fish fillet</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hitting the Gym</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2022-05-23-Hitting-the-Gym/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Over the past 2-3 years I've being working out consistently.
Outside.
Running and body-weights.
I worked out 4-5 days per week.
Alternating between running and body-weights.</p>
<p>But after the moving, my workout process was disrupted.
Because I couldn't find a place near new place to do them.
There is a PCN nearby.
But on one side it has a bridge, and other side a road crossing.
Not so ideal for running.
And I couldn't find any suitable park to do the body-weights in the neighborhood.</p>
<p>So I decided to go the office gym.
Up to this point I always tried to avoid going to Gym.
Because I wanted to not to tied to gym for working out.</p>
<p>But then again why should I tied to doing body-weights.</p>
<p>So I booked the Gym for 5 days (starting May 16).
First week was just exploring the machines and building a habit.
Running on treadmill felt quite different to outdoor running.
And I was afraid to let go of the rail.
So I just walked on the treadmill.
First holding to the rail.
Then without.
By the end of week I was able to run about 1k without holding to the rail.
I also tried few body-weights(pull ups and rows).
That's for the first week.</p>
<p>Now I'm in the middle of the 2nd week.
I did 5k treadmill run on Monday.
And tried the beginners routing on reddit/fitness wiki on Tuesday.
I tried the Set A which include, barbel rows, bench-press and Squats with just the barbell bar(20kg)
It felt good and I feel body is responding to the exercises.
Today is Wednesday and I'm Planing to do another 5k Run today.
Plan is to alternate weights and cardio.
Tomorrow I'll try the set B,
which includes dead-lift, chin-ups and overhead-press.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Moving</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2022-05-04-Moving/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>May 1st 2022 I moved to a new place.
I've being at my previous place for 2+ years.
It was a rented HDB flat at Houagang, with some of my friends.
During my stay rent was changed between 400 - 1100 SGD.
Depending on the number of tenants at the period and the house rent.
The last rent I paid was 2400SGD/5 = 480SGD</p>
<p>My new place is a common room at Condominium in Aljunied.
New place costs 1300SGD - 50 = 1250SGD.
So it's roughly 3x of the old price.</p>
<p>I managed to pack all my belongings to 1 checking luggage plus 2 hand luggages.
Except for the PC and 3 pair of shoes.
1 hand luggage is filled with almost useless stuff.
Should clear it sometime.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Camping at Pulau Ubin</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2022-04-17-Camping-at-Pulau-Ubin/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>This was the latest situation where I waited most anxiously for sun rise.
(Previous one is at Adams Peak)</p>
<h3>Why</h3>
<p>It's long weekend.
My housemates and I wanted do something different.
We had few plans for travel(Singapore is opening up after covid travel restrictions)
Including Japan, Indonesia, Malaysia.
But unfortunate cross country travel is still hard(due to covid restrictions)
So we decided to go camping in the most rural island in Singapore, Pulau-Ubin.</p>
<h3>Preparation</h3>
<p>Charged the Camera.
Packed few clothes, foods and off we go.</p>
<h3>Journey to Pulau-Ubin.</h3>
<p>We get into the bus around 4pm(plan was to start at 2pm).
Reached Changi Beach Point at 5pm.
Had food, did shopping(mainly drinking water and more food).
Got into to ferry close to 7pm.
It charged 48 SGD for the ride.
Us 5 were the only passengers.
After some 20 minutes we landed at Pulau-Ubin.</p>
<h3>Finding a camp site.</h3>
<p>We rented bikes(6 SGD each) and went to the closest camp site.
It was almost full.
Then proceed to the next closest one.(about 2.5km away)
Plan was to get there by nightfall.
Which we failed to.
As it was already dark after 10 minutes we started riding.
Eventually we got to the campsite,
After only witnessing a wild boar crossing the road.
(We also passed some closed down old houses too)</p>
<p>But alas,
The camp site is closed.
No option but to return to the 1st camp site(in dark)
We didn't see any more wild boars.
(Guess it was impossible to see the boars given we hardly saw the road we were riding).
Or anything else interesting.
We reached to the 1st campsite, and choose the hut at the farther end of the campsite.
And noticed everybody else have bought tents!!!</p>
<h3>Camping.</h3>
<p>We unpacked our stuff at the hut and observe what fellow campers are doing.
Which was hard due to darkness.
Time was around 9pm I guess.
Some people were trying fix camps and hammocks.
Some were cooking in camp fires.
We tried to find some dry wood(which turns out to be impossible) to make a fire.
We later found out there are designated fire pits, with a supply dry wood.
Then we tried to fix our hammock,
After some struggle we managed to.
But getting into the hammock and relaxing wasn't possible.
Because the ropes which held the hammock to poles tend to slip along the poles.
So we put the bags into hammock,
And try to sit/lie on the short walls of the hut.
Time was around 10pm now.
With 8 more hours until the sunrise,
we noticed some kind of insect started having us for the dinner.
Couldn't be mosquitoes because those didn't has that annoying noise.
(By now we were regretting the decision to camp)</p>
<h3>Camp fire.</h3>
<p>After 10.30 fellow campers (like good Singaporeans) stopped what they were doing and got into tents to sleep.
Which was not an option for us since we didn't have a tent.
After some more minutes(felt like hours) we gathered around a recently vacated fire pit and relit it.
Fire made the atmosphere more lighter and discouraged the insects.
But there were 7 more hours until the first boat out.</p>
<h3>Until 7am</h3>
<p>We discovered it's just impossible to sit around a fire for 7 hours, so we thought about checking out if the shops in jetty area is still open.
They were closed.
But we met a drunk woman who said we were cute and asked to join us.
Unfortunately which we didn't understand.
So we said no.
Which made her quite unhappy(And us after we figured what's the question was).
We went to the jetty and watch people fishing.</p>
<h3>Russian Musician</h3>
<p>Came back to the out camp fire to find 2 guys singing and playing guitar there.
Who turned out to be one guitarist + singer and his friend.
Guitarist is a Russian student and he could play German and English songs as well as Russian songs.
His friend was from US.
Singer would give out a explanation after every song he sang.
We sat and listened for a while.
Then we started talking, about politics
Russian started blaming Putin(for attacking Ukraine),
US, Biden(for supporting Ukraine) and we(not to be outdone), our president.
This went for a while and they went to sleep around 4am,
After bidding us good night.</p>
<h3>Morning</h3>
<p>We tried to catch some sleep.
And around 5.30am packed out stuff and came to jetty.
And tried to nap there.
First boat was due at 7am.
Soon another camper joined us at the jetty.
As there is still some time left for the boat,
I with a friend, went to see if the shops are opened.
Which they were and we had a hot tea there,
It started raining by the time we finished the tea.
Around 6.45am friends stayed at jetty called us saying a boat is coming.
So we went back to jetty in the rain and got in to the boat.
There were 6 passengers in the boat.
Passage back to mainland was uneventful though the sea was rough.</p>
<h3>Getting home</h3>
<p>Once got off,
Booked a taxi.
Got home.
Showered.
Had food.
Slept.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>PC</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2022-03-07-PC/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>On the last Christmas day I built a PC.
Building a powerful PC was a childhood dream of mine,
since I started playing PC games.</p>
<p>So on the Christmas day(2021) I came to office.
Plan was to buy the parts and build on my own.
The parts shop was near to the office.
So It's easier to bring the parts to office, build and transfer the whole unit to home.</p>
<p>I went to shop and bought,</p>
<ul>
<li>Gigabyte B550i AOURUS PRO AX AM4 ITX Motherboard</li>
<li>AMD Ryzen 7 5800X 3.8Ghz</li>
<li>Crucial ballistix Gaming 3600MHz 32GB(16GBx2) CL 16</li>
<li>WD Black sn 750 SE 1TB GEN4 M.2 NVMe SSD</li>
<li>ASUS GT 1030 2GB</li>
<li>Cooler master masterbox NR200P Max casing with 850W gold PSU and 280MM IO</li>
</ul>
<p>Total price was 1900 SGD.
I wanted to buy a RTX3080.
But the prices are 2000+ SGD for MSRP 1100 SGD card.
So Decided to wait until price come down.</p>
<p>I bought the parts to office.
Unpacked and started putting them together.
Installing the cooler into cpu was the most difficult.</p>
<p>After about 2 hours all the parts are put together.
I booted the system.
It didn't start up. :(</p>
<p>I re-install the power cables.
Still no luck.
Ever power unit fan is not working.
I unplugged all the power cables.
Short the power unit.
No sign of working.</p>
<p>Time was close to 8pm now.
I packed the PC and dragged it to the parts shop.
Guy in the shop said they are planning to close down shop and leave the PC there.</p>
<p>But I insisted.
I wanted it to be done with.
So finally they offered help.</p>
<p>He started pulling the cables and putting them back.
And started the PC.
It booted!!! :D
I thanked him whole heartedly and bought the PC back to office, and then home.</p>
<p>Since then I've installed Windows 10 and few games on it.
But the GPU is quite a bottle neck.
It's not possible the play recent AAA games due to GPU limitation.
But it can comfortable play old titles like</p>
<ul>
<li>GTA 5</li>
<li>NFS Most wanted</li>
</ul>
<p>Which will do until GPU prices come down(hopefully)</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>2021 Retrospective</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2021-12-31-2021-Retrospective/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Today is the final day of 2021.
It's being a quite interesting year, to say the least.
Mostly stuck at home.
Pretty sure I was depressed, at least slightly, in the first part of the year.</p>
<p>Apart from that, in year 2021 I,</p>
<ul>
<li>Shot, processed and published 32 sets of <a href="/photos">photos</a>.</li>
<li>Wrote (whole lot of) 1 blog post.</li>
<li>Bought a GoPro, with plans to building a documentary of my day-to-day life.</li>
<li>Build a gaming PC, which was a childhood dream and will facilitate editing videos/photos.</li>
<li>Set up a home theater with a projector+roku stick and a media server.</li>
<li>Bought a Garmin Fenix 6, to help my running training.</li>
<li>Run 687km this year.</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/assets/running.png" alt="full-width" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Including 2 races.</li>
</ul>
<p>In-person 5k</p>
<p><img src="/assets/2021_5k.png" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>And a virtual half marathon.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/2021_half_marathon.png" alt="full-width" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Cycled 462km</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/assets/cycling.png" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>So again, It's being an interesting year.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Long Day</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2021-08-21-Long-Day/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Today I'm having an unusual long day.
Long because I woke up at 5am.
First time after coming to Singapore(3 years ago).
Unusual because I usually wake up after sun made 1/4th of his daily journey.</p>
<p>I wanted to change this late wakeup habit for some time.
But didn't have enough will power I guess.
I set the alarm and go to bed with plans to wake up early.
But the next morning me is not a guy with a plan at all.
And this working from home thing(due to covid restrictions) made is worse.
Because of the flexibility it allowed,
I have no external reason to get up early.</p>
<p>With all this I did wake up early today.
After a ~3 hour sleep at that.</p>
<p>I had an external reason to get up early today.
I(and my friends) had to prepare a morning meal to a temple.
It's common ritual among Buddhists.
We do it for multiple reasons.
This time it's because one of My friend's father died.
Friend I didn't physically meet for 3+ years now.
We believe offering food to monks will give good karma to the departed.</p>
<p>So 2 hours later we(I and my 2 friends) cooked the food and sent it to temple.
It's 7am.
I could have gone back to bed(it's Saturday after all).
My friends did go to bed.</p>
<p>But I didn't.
I wanted to build on this.
I took breakfast, got the bike out and went for a dopamine fix.
My plan was to reward the brain.
So it might help me to wake up early tomorrow.</p>
<p>I did 15km ride in 1 hour and 18 minutes.
It wasn't not that fun,
because the weather was gloomy.</p>
<p>Came home, had a shower.
Did the daily consumption of news.
Read bit from Lord of the Rings(much better than the movie)
And fixed the lunch.
Note that my friends are still asleep.(poor guys missing all the fun)
They got up when I was having lunch.</p>
<p>Then I set to work.
I had 4 sets of unprocessed photos.
I processed them and published(here).
After that I noticed I am yet to do a blog post for this year.
So started writing this,</p>
<p>It's 4.45pm now.
Fingers crossed for tomorrow.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>[paper]A Few Useful Things to Know About Machine Learning</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-12-24-[paper]A-Few-Useful-Things-to-Know-About-Machine-Learning/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Machine Learning has lots of folk wisdom, which acquired from doing it.
This paper is trying to give explain some of that wisdom.</p>
<h4>Learning = Representation + Evaluation + Optimization</h4>
<p>All ML algorithms contain 3 components and 3 components only,</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Representation
Representation of the algorithm in a formal computer language. This is equally important as choosing the set of classifiers(hypothesis space) it can possibly learn.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Evaluation
Evaluation function is required to find the good classification from bad ones.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Optimization
Search the classifiers to find the best scoring one.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h4>It's Generalization that Counts</h4>
<p>Generalization is important because it's impossible to have all the possibilities at the training time. It's required to divide the data in a meaningful way to do the train and test. Else not possible to achieve generalization.</p>
<h4>Data alone is not enough</h4>
<p>Even though ML is data driven technique, a domain knowledge is also required. Mainly because it's not possible have enough data to represent all the outcomes.</p>
<h4>Overfitting has many faces</h4>
<p>Overfitting is failure to generalize. Optimum is to have a low bias, low variance model. Cross-validation can help to avoid overfitting.</p>
<h4>Intuition fails in high dimensions</h4>
<p>As the number of dimensions grow it becomes exponentially  harder to generalize.</p>
<h4>Theoretical guarantees are not what they seem</h4>
<p>ML is induction. So unlike in deduction, there is no guarantee the conclusion is correct. Just because a learner has theoretical justification and works doesn't mean the justification is the reason for it to work.</p>
<h4>Feature engineering is the key</h4>
<p>Learning is easy when there are many independent features that correlate well with the class. So selecting correct features is important. It requires domain knowledge for this.</p>
<h4>More data beats a cleverer algorithm</h4>
<p>Even when the feature set is finalized, if the model is not working, there are 2 possibilities to try. 1)add more data. 2)design a better algorithm. Doing the former is easier.</p>
<h4>Learn many models, not just one</h4>
<p>Instead of selecting the best model, combining many variation often works better. And this is different for Bayesian model averaging.</p>
<h4>Simplicity does not imply accuracy</h4>
<p>There is no connection between number of parameters in the model and its tendency to overfit.</p>
<h4>Representable does not imply learnable</h4>
<p>More important question is can it be learnable.</p>
<h4>Correlation does not imply causation</h4>
<p>ML is applied to observational data. Though some learning algorithms can potentially extract causal information for observational data, their applicability is rather restricted. Treating the correlation as a sign of potential connection is the way to go.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Printing On Ricoh C5503 from Macbook</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-12-22-Printing-On-Ricoh-C5503-from-Macbook/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I have access to a Ricoh 5503 printer.
It works fine with windows.
It used to work fine with Linux.
But didn't work with Mac.
Then it stopped working on Linux(After updating to 20.04)</p>
<p>Since I didn't have a windows PC, I set upon to make it work on Mac.(I'm using a office issued macbook primarily for work)
After some googling I found this post<a href="https://community.spiceworks.com/topic/1060351-having-issues-printing-off-of-a-ricoh-mp-c5503-and-ricoh-mp-c3003">https://community.spiceworks.com/topic/1060351-having-issues-printing-off-of-a-ricoh-mp-c5503-and-ricoh-mp-c3003</a></p>
<p>I followed the (relevant to big sur anyways) steps and it worked!!!</p>
<p>What I did exactly is,</p>
<ol>
<li>Key in the ip address in <code>Address</code> field.</li>
<li>Set the <code>Protocol</code> to IPP</li>
<li>Set the <code>Use</code> to Generic PCL Printer.</li>
<li><code>Add</code> the printer.</li>
</ol>
<p>It asked me whether I want to use it as a Duplexer and I said yes.</p>
<p>That's all.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>[paper] bitcoin</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-12-18-[paper]-bitcoin/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<h4>Transaction</h4>
<p>How to do a transaction</p>
<ol>
<li>get the hash of the previous transaction</li>
<li>get the next owner's public key</li>
<li>combine them together</li>
<li>sign the combined hash with own private key</li>
</ol>
<p>But still the payee can't verify the payer didn't do a double spend.
To guaranty there is no double spend all the transactions are made public.
Then it's required for all the peers to agree on a single history of the order which transactions happened.</p>
<h4>Timestamp Server</h4>
<p>Get a block of data and hash it, then publish the hash with the current time stamp.</p>
<h4>proof of work</h4>
<p>To make this timestamp server work peer-to-peer, it requires a proof of work to do a hash.
This proof-of-work is that each hash should have a certain number of 0s at the beginning.
How to achieve this is,</p>
<ul>
<li>each block has a digit which can be increased.</li>
<li>the node hash the block, check if the hash has the necessary number of 0s.</li>
<li>if not increase the digit.</li>
<li>it follows this procedure until it gets the necessary number of 0s.</li>
</ul>
<p>So once the hashing done for a block, to tamper it this proof-of-work has to be repeated.
And as the new blocks are added to the chain, it gets harder to tamper old blocks (because it will require to change the hash of all the blocks after that tampered block).
This way the longest chain of blocks represent the majority vote.
To compensate for increasing hardware power, and varying interest in running a node the difficulty of the proof-of-work is changed based on average number of blocks per hour.</p>
<h4>Network</h4>
<ol>
<li>New transactions are broadcast to all nodes.</li>
<li>Each node collects new transactions into a block.</li>
<li>Each node works on finding a difficult proof-of-work for its block.</li>
<li>When a node finds a proof-of-work, it broadcasts the block to all nodes.</li>
<li>Nodes accept the block only if all transactions in it are valid and not already spent.</li>
<li>Nodes express their acceptance of the block by working on creating the next block in the
chain, using the hash of the accepted block as the previous hash.</li>
</ol>
<h4>incentive</h4>
<p>will come from mining new coins and doing transactions.</p>
<h4>reclaiming disk space</h4>
<p>transactions are hashed in a merkle tree, only root includes the blocks hash.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Running on 2020</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-12-17-Running-on-2020/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Yesterday I stopped running for few months.
This is me bragging about my running on 2020.</p>
<p>I started this running season somewhere on April.
Mostly because there isn't anything else to do (stuck at home due to covid restrictions).</p>
<p>Around May I came across the book &quot;Running Formula&quot; by &quot;Jack Daniels&quot; and started practicing + tracking runs.
By the June <a href="https://kasungamlath.com/blog/Stats-for-Half-Month-of-Running/">I did 5k</a>.
I stopped the practicing by the book once I made it to a certain level.
(There were bunch of ranking levels in the book)</p>
<p>And started running for just fun.</p>
<p>Then came the virtual runs.
Idea of virtual run is you sign up for a certain distance to do within a certain time period.</p>
<p>I did few of them.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://kasungamlath.com/blog/Virtual-Marathon/">SMU SwimRunSprint</a>(no swimming this year)
<img src="/assets/marathon.png" alt="full-width" /></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>SMOO Challenge
<img src="/assets/smoo.png" alt="full-width" /></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Straits Times virtual run 17.5km
<img src="/assets/stvr17.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Straits Times virtual run 175km
<img src="/assets/stvr175.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Longest run I did is a <a href="https://kasungamlath.com/blog/Half-Marathon/">half marathon</a>(which took almost 3 hours).
With a pretty bad pace.</p>
<p>Now it's time for go back to book again and improve the pace(after few months rest)</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>On reading papers</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-12-16-On-reading-papers/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<ul>
<li>Advice on reading academic papers - <a href="https://www.cc.gatech.edu/~akmassey/posts/2012-02-15-advice-on-reading-academic-papers.html">https://www.cc.gatech.edu/~akmassey/posts/2012-02-15-advice-on-reading-academic-papers.html</a></li>
<li>How to read and understand a scientific paper: a guide for non-scientists - <a href="https://violentmetaphors.com/2013/08/25/how-to-read-and-understand-a-scientific-paper-2/">https://violentmetaphors.com/2013/08/25/how-to-read-and-understand-a-scientific-paper-2/</a></li>
<li>reading list for CS 240B and the approximate order in which we will read them - <a href="http://mcvoy.com/lm/papers/stanford.txt">http://mcvoy.com/lm/papers/stanford.txt</a></li>
<li>(video) The Refreshingly Rewarding Realm of Research Papers - <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8eRx5Wo3xYA">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8eRx5Wo3xYA</a></li>
<li>(git repo) Papers we love - <a href="https://github.com/papers-we-love/papers-we-love">https://github.com/papers-we-love/papers-we-love</a></li>
<li>Anotated papers - <a href="https://fermatslibrary.com/">https://fermatslibrary.com/</a></li>
</ul>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>[paper]Edge Computing in 5G: A Review</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-12-15-[paper]Edge-Computing-in-5G:-A-Review/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Edge computing enables 5G to bring cloud computing to near the end users.
This in turn fixes the issues of traditional cloud - high latency, lack of security.</p>
<p>Traditional cloud computing extends the computing/storage abilities of the user equipments(UEs).
But fails when high quality of service(QoS) - low latency, hight throughput required.
Edge servers in mini clouds are designed to address these QoS failures.</p>
<h3>Background</h3>
<h4>Requirements of 5G system</h4>
<p>5G networks possesses 3 main new characteristics(compared to old generations)</p>
<ol>
<li>Massive amount of data get generated - due to increased number of mobile devices.</li>
<li>Tight QoS requirements - due to high interactive applications.</li>
<li>Heterogeneous environment support - due to diverse range of UEs.</li>
</ol>
<p>3 main technologies</p>
<ol>
<li>mmWave communication - 30-300GHz</li>
<li>Small cells deployment - to reduce interference and transmission range.</li>
<li>Massive multi-input multi-output (MIMO) - allows base stations (BSs) to use upto 16 antennas per sector to provide directional transmission.</li>
</ol>
<h4>Main characteristics of 5G data</h4>
<ul>
<li>Hard real-time - ie video streaming, gaming, healthcare services. Need to be handled in edge servers.</li>
<li>Soft real-time - can tolerate latency upto some pre-defined limit. ie: intelligent traffic signal control system. Depending on latency requirement will chose where to be handled.</li>
<li>Non-real-time - can be offloaded to remote cloud.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Significance of edge computing</h4>
<ul>
<li>Provide sub ms latency</li>
<li>Reduce the energy consumption</li>
</ul>
<h4>4 Key requirements of edge computing in 5G</h4>
<ol>
<li>real-time interaction - remote surgery, tactile internet(internet network that combines ultra low latency with extremely high availability, reliability and security)</li>
<li>local processing - reduce the traffic to core network</li>
<li>high data rate - between user devices and edge clouds and between edge clouds and edge serves (embedded in the base station)</li>
<li>hight availability</li>
</ol>
<h4>Applications of edge computing in 5G</h4>
<ul>
<li>Healthcare - remote surgery, diagnostics</li>
<li>High bandwidth entertainment</li>
<li>VR, AR and mixed reality</li>
<li>Tactile internet (ultra-responsive and ultra-reliable network)</li>
<li>URLLC(ultra reliable low latency communication) - high  reliability  between UEs specifically in M2M communications</li>
<li>IoT</li>
<li>Factories of the future</li>
<li>Emergency response</li>
<li>Intelligent transportation system - drivers share/gather information from traffic information centers in real-time manner to avoid accidents.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Taxonomy</h3>
<h4>5 main objectives</h4>
<ol>
<li>Improving data management - large amounts with low latency</li>
<li>Improve QoS</li>
<li>Predicting network demand</li>
<li>Managing location awareness - infer own locations for edge serves and track the location of UEs</li>
<li>Improve resource management - to optimize resource utilization.</li>
</ol>
<h4>3 main computational platforms</h4>
<ol>
<li>Cloud computing</li>
<li>Edge computing
<ol>
<li>Fog computing -  system-level horizontal architecture that distributes resources and services of computing,storage, control, and networking anywhere along the continuum from cloud to things</li>
<li>MEC (mobile edge computing)</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Hybrid</li>
</ol>
<h4>3 main attributes</h4>
<ol>
<li>Low latency and close proximity</li>
<li>Location awareness</li>
<li>Network context awareness</li>
</ol>
<h4>Use of 5G functions</h4>
<ol>
<li>Software-defined network - network architecture that separates a network into control and data planes to provide flexible and agile networks. Simplify network management</li>
<li>Network function virtualization</li>
<li>Massive MIMO</li>
<li>Dynamic access to radio access technologies</li>
<li>D2D communication - without passing through BS</li>
</ol>
<h4>Performance measures</h4>
<ol>
<li>Lower operational cost - by providing local functions</li>
<li>Higher QoS - by providing local functions (same way it lowers operational cost)</li>
<li>Energy efficiency - by providing local functions (same way it facilitates above two)</li>
</ol>
<h4>Role of edge computing in 5G</h4>
<ol>
<li>Local storage</li>
<li>Local computation</li>
<li>Local data analysis</li>
<li>Local design making</li>
<li>Local operation</li>
<li>Local security enhancement</li>
</ol>
<h3>State of the art</h3>
<h4>Fog based solutions</h4>
<ul>
<li>cross-layer resource management scheme is presented between optical network and fog computing over fiber networks - in order to incorporate delay requirements to edge servers. Improves QoS, resource management by providing local computation.</li>
<li>an architecture that enables edge servers to provide caching, computing, and communications functions (also known as 3Cs) is proposed so that content and service providers can deploy their functions, services, and content closed to UEs.</li>
</ul>
<h4>MEC based solutions</h4>
<ul>
<li>architecture is presented to perform energy-aware offloading, whereby each mobile UE decides whether to per-form or offload computational tasks to MEC server, in order to reduce energy consumption of MEC</li>
<li>MEC services are autonomously created by the nearest edge server in order to provide mobile UEs with seamless QoE in video streaming.</li>
<li>D2D architecture is proposed for a mas-sive number of UEs to execute collaborative tasks in an energy-efficient manner.</li>
<li>predictive and proactive caching approach is introduced in order to reduce peak traffic demands</li>
<li>application-aware traffic redirection mechanism is proposed for MEC in order to reduce response time and bandwidth consumption.</li>
<li>virtualized multi-access edge computing frame-work is proposed to increase available bandwidth and reduces end-to-end delay in an intelligent manner in Internet of things.</li>
<li>fiber wireless (FiWi) access architecture is introduced to improve MEC services</li>
<li>a group of vehicular neighboring nodes (or VNG)is dynamically managed using SDN to improve control over network and its resources in vehicular networks</li>
<li>a non-standalone (i.e., disconnected from the Inter-net) MEC-based architecture is presented for mission-critical public safety services in order to achieve the delay requirement (i.e., less than 1 ms (ideal) or 10 ms (maximum) of round trip time) of 5G.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Hybrid solutions</h4>
<ul>
<li>D2D-based mobile edge and fog computing architecture is introduced to enable collaborative computing,which performs tasks in more than a single computing plat-forms or paradigms, in order to enhance MEC</li>
<li>context-aware, real-time collaborative architecture is proposed to manage heterogeneous resources (e.g., different storage and computational capabilities in different computational platforms/ layers) at the edge of the net-work.</li>
<li>real-time, context-aware, service-composition,and collaborative architecture is proposed to deliver fast composite service, which is the consolidation of multiple services supported by the collaboration of different hardware(e.g., UEs, edge clouds, and cloud) and software with different capabilities.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Open research issues</h3>
<ul>
<li>Service enhancement: QoE - challenge is to achieve a balanced trade-off between a) high availability - seamless connectivity b) higher QoE</li>
<li>Standardization of protocols</li>
<li>Addressing heterogeneity - Heterogeneity in communication (e.g., transmission range and data rate) and computing (e.g., hardware architecture and operating systems) technologies in edge computing for 5G has resulted in difficulties in developing a solution that is portable across different environment.</li>
<li>Security and privacy - two main problems that can increase network vulnerability at the edge 1)dynamic environment causes the data and network requirements of different network entities to vary rapidly 2)increasing number of devices communicating with each other must require a scalable solution.</li>
</ul>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Half Marathon</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-12-14-Half-Marathon/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Early this month I ran a half marathon.
Though I did it without stoping it took almost 3 hours.
Average pace is 8 min per kilo meter.
For the context world record for the marathon is just under 2 hours.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/21km.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>But still I feel this is a long way since me celebrating doing a (almost)5k in just 6 months ago.</p>
<p>This will be the longest run I'm doing in 2020.
I need to improve the pace before doing another.</p>
<p>I also met a huge wild boar during this run.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>[paper]Computer vision syndrome</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-12-14-[paper]Computer-vision-syndrome/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Mark-Rosenfield/publication/295902618_Computer_vision_syndrome_aka_digital_eye_strain/links/56cf685008ae4d8d649fc316/Computer-vision-syndrome-aka-digital-eye-strain.pdf">link to the paper</a></p>
<h3>Gaze Angle</h3>
<p>At the eye examination, difficulty to replicate the specific gaze used when viewing the digital devices is an issue.
Because users view different displays in different angles, ie laptop display - downward angle, desktop monitors - primary gaze, mobile phone - almost any direction.</p>
<h3>Text Size</h3>
<p>acuity reserve is required to to allow comfortable reading.
ie for sustained comfortable reading text size should be at least twice the individuals visual acuity.</p>
<h3>Glare</h3>
<p>Reflection on display is bad.
Place the screens perpendicular to fluorescent tubes.
Don't place display directly in-front of or behind unshaded windows.</p>
<h3>Correcting Refractive Errors</h3>
<p>This is challenging because the required working distance vary from 70 - 17.5cm(form desktop to smartphone).
It's also important to correct even the small amount of astigmatism(eye does not focus light evenly on the retina. This results in distorted or blurred vision at any distance) when using digital displays.</p>
<h3>Accommodation and Convergence</h3>
<p>since the near vision demands when using viewing digital screens are significant, a comprehensive assessment of accommodation and vergence system should be included for all digital screen users.
Hart chart test is a good way to test the flexibility of accommodation and vergence.</p>
<h3>Dry Eye</h3>
<p>Environmental factors - low ambient humidity, high forced-air heating, high air-conditioning settings, use of ventilation fans, excess static electricity or airborne contaminants.
Increased corneal exposure - displays used with eyes in primary position.
Prevalence of dry eye increases with age and is higher in women.
Systemic diseases and medications - arthritis, allergy , thyroid disease, taking antihistamines, antianxiety medications, antidepressants, oral steroids or vitamins.</p>
<h3>Blink Rate</h3>
<p>Blink rate get reduced using computer operation. 22/min - relaxed, 10/min , 7/min when viewing book or screen.
Blink rate also get reduced when viewing decreased fond size and when contrast is reduced or the cognitive demand of task is increased.
Beading identical text on hardcopy vs digital display didn't result in different blink rates.
But digital displays resulted a higher level of incomplete blinks(may be due to eye in primary position)</p>
<h3>Asthenopia(weakness or easy fatigue of the eye)</h3>
<p>Symptoms commonly associated with this diagnostic term included eye strain, eye fatigue, discomfort, burning, irritation, pain, ache, sore eyes, diplopia, photophobia, blur, itching, tearing, dryness and foreign-body sensation.</p>
<h3>The Blue Light Hypothesis</h3>
<p>There is no published evidence that blue light emitted from digital displays cause DES, but it's being suggested.
Blue light is generally considered to comprise wavelengths between 380 and approximately 500nm.
Human retina is protected from short-wavelength radiation.
Exposure to blue light has been widely reported to be involved in the regulation of circadian rhythm and the sleep cycle.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>[book]Dune by Frank Herbert</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-09-28-[book]Dune-by-Frank-Herbert/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>A world is is supported by four things ...'
She held up four big knuckled fingers.
'... the learning of the wise, the justice of the great,
the prayers of the righteous and the valor of the brave.
But all of these are as nothing ...'
She closed her fingers into a fist.
`... without a ruler who knows the art of ruling.
-Reverend Mother(Not lady Jessica)</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stir Fried Oyster Mushroom</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-09-20-Stir-Fried-Oyster-Mushroom/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Final results.
( ͡° ͜ʖ ͡°)</p>
<p><img src="/assets/mushroom1.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>(Sorry, I forgot to take a picture before eating)</p>
<p>Ingredients</p>
<ul>
<li>Oyster mushroom - 2 packets</li>
<li>Green chilli - 5</li>
<li>Red onion - 4</li>
<li>Pandang leaves</li>
<li>Curry leaf</li>
<li>Garlic - 4 pieces</li>
<li>Curry powder - 1 table spoon</li>
<li>Chilli powder - 1/2 table spoon</li>
<li>Pepper powder - 1/4 table spoon</li>
<li>Salt</li>
<li>Turmeric - 1/4 table spoon</li>
</ul>
<p>Method</p>
<ol>
<li>Peel the mushroom like below(to absorb the spices better)
<img src="/assets/mushroom2.jpg" alt="full-width" /></li>
<li>Wash the peeled mushroom in hot water.</li>
<li>Burn the curry powder and chilli powder until they are dark brown.</li>
<li>Add curry powder, chilli powder, pepper, salt and turmeric to mushroom and mix it well.
<img src="/assets/mushroom3.jpg" alt="full-width" /></li>
<li>Clean up and chop the other ingredients as well.(Image contains ingredients for another dish too)
<img src="/assets/mushroom4.jpg" alt="full-width" /></li>
<li>Heat the wok.</li>
<li>Add coconut oil few(2-3) table spoons.</li>
<li>When oil is heated add chopped garlic, pandang leaves, curry leaves.</li>
<li>When garlic is turning to brownish color add chopped red onion.</li>
<li>Stir well and once the mixture is fried enough add green chilli and prepared mushroom.</li>
<li>Mix well.</li>
<li>Add bit of water.</li>
<li>Close the wok.</li>
<li>Let it cook for about 15 minutes(make sure to check periodically it's not being burnt).</li>
</ol>
<p>Congratulation!! Now you know how to cook delicious spicy stir fried mushroom.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>[paper]Digital eye strain:prevalence, measurement and amelioration</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-09-03-[paper]Digital-eye-strain:prevalence,-measurement-and-amelioration/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Digital Eye Stain (DES) have estimated prevalence of 50% or more among Computer Users.
Symptoms fall in to 2 categories.</p>
<ol>
<li>due to accommodative or binocular vision stress</li>
<li>due to dry eye</li>
</ol>
<p>Symptoms are typical transient.</p>
<p>There are several available questionnaires to identify and measure DES.
It also can be measured and identify by using objective evaluations of bellow parameters</p>
<ul>
<li>critical flicker-fusion frequency.</li>
<li>blink rate and completeness.</li>
<li>accommodative function and pupil characteristics</li>
</ul>
<p>Sometimes the correlation between objective and subjective measures are not apparent.</p>
<p>Range of management approaches available for DES</p>
<ul>
<li>correction of refractive error and/or presbyopia</li>
<li>management of dry eye</li>
<li>incorporating regular screen breaks</li>
<li>consideration of vergence and accommodative problems</li>
</ul>
<p>DES and visual fatigue(VF) is used for Computer Vision Syndrom(CVS).</p>
<p>In 2016 UK adults typically spend 4hours 45mins per day staring at screens.
USA it's about 5 or more hours</p>
<p>Most common symptoms associated with DES are,</p>
<ul>
<li>eyestrain (asthenopia)</li>
<li>headache</li>
<li>blurred vission</li>
<li>dry eyes</li>
<li>pain in the neck and shoulders</li>
</ul>
<p>DES is very common problem
2016 Digital Eye Stain report with 10,000 US adults</p>
<ul>
<li>65% total</li>
<li>69% of female</li>
<li>60% of male</li>
<li>73% who uses 2 or more devices simultaneously</li>
<li>53% single device</li>
</ul>
<p>When computer use is 6 or more hours,
contact wearers are more likely to affected(65% vs 50%)</p>
<p>Widely dissimilar diagnostic criteria for DED means the overall figures have a limited value.
There are recent detailed recommendation for diagnostic methodology</p>
<ul>
<li>first symptom screening with ocular surface disease index or dry eye questionnaire(DEQ-5) instruments</li>
<li>then objective clinical tests in in DED suspects</li>
</ul>
<h2>Measuring DES</h2>
<h3>subjective</h3>
<ul>
<li>10 item questionnaire created by Hayes</li>
<li>six item visual fatigue scale</li>
<li>Rasch based computer vision symptom scale</li>
<li>validated questionnaire in english to evaluate DES in workspace</li>
<li>self administered computer vision syndrome questionnaire</li>
</ul>
<h3>objective</h3>
<ul>
<li>critical flicker fusion frequency
<ul>
<li>the frequency which a flickering light is indistinguishable from a steady non-flickering light. reduced activity of the retina and/or optic nerve can cause this frequency number to decrease</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Blinking characteristics
<ul>
<li>blinking helps to maintain normal ocular surface. before computer use mean - 18.4, during computer use - 3.6. incomplete blinks can also cause the dry eyes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Accommodative effects
<ul>
<li>pre-prebyopes must be able to accommodate rapidly+smoothly and maintain a accurate response to perform near tasks comfortably. But when viewing computer displays this accomadation shows a lag.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>pupillary light relex and size
<ul>
<li>increase of pupil size indicates visual fatigue.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2>Mangement of Dry Eye</h2>
<p>use of lubricating eye drops reduce tiredness dryness and difficulty focusing.
dietary supplementaion with omega-3 fatty acids
blink training may help, (Increasing blink rate through use of an audible prompt signal every 4s during a computer task was not found to alter  symptom  score)
blink efficiency exercise to address incomplete blinks may helpfull
fix issures related to refractive error and fresbyopia - spectacles for screen use
fix accommodation and vergence anomalies - frequent short breaks,
blue light - exposure to blue light (400-500nm) can be harmful to the retina. melatonin involved in physiological ctrl of sleep. it's controlled by photosensitive retinal ganflion cells containing melanopsin, which has a peak sensitivity of approximately 482nm.</p>
<h2>conclusion</h2>
<p>usage is digital devices is norm today.
this leads to DES.
it's important eye care practitioners are well informed about this.
DES symtoms are linked to
1. external - dry eye
2. internal - related to ameropia, accommodation or vergence problems.
questionaires are valueble in evluating DES.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Virtual Marathon</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-08-14-Virtual-Marathon/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I was checking the mails on July 20 morning and saw an email about a virtual marathon.</p>
<p>How it happens is, within 25 days (20July - 15 Aug) finish either of the bellow distances.</p>
<ul>
<li>5 km</li>
<li>10 km</li>
<li>20.1 km</li>
<li>42.2 km</li>
<li>78.3 km</li>
</ul>
<p>It doesn't even has to be a continuous run.</p>
<p>As a proof it's required to upload a screenshot of the run recorded by approved mobile app.</p>
<p>As I have already being running about 20km per week I chose to run 78.3 km.
Fees for the participation in 78.3 km distance was 30 SGD.</p>
<p>I registered for the event.
Then started running and submitting the screenshots.</p>
<p>Today I got a email saying that I have completed the distance.</p>
<p>So there's another first in my life, running a virtual marathon.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/marathon.png" alt="camera-photo" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fullmoon and Teapot</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-08-12-Fullmoon-and-Teapot/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I'm working on building a testbed to evaluate some hypothesis related to a smart light project.
This test bed involves a cctv camera and multiple adjustable light sources.
Light sources are LEDs which made adjustable by connecting to raspberry pi units.
Then leveraging the (P)ulse (W)idth (M)odulation to adjust the brightness.
In addition to light source there are also lux sensors(bh1750) plugged into raspberry pi.</p>
<p>The design of the software system is to make the raspberry pi units as much as dumb.
So it only does the bare minimum required.
Reason behind this is troubleshooting, deploying and maintaining the system resources on these raspberry pi units are bit difficult.
Then using a server as a central processor to do the rest.</p>
<p>For the raspberry pi I developed a tiny web server named <strong>teapot</strong>.
And for the central processor a application named <strong>fullmoon</strong>.</p>
<p>Teapot is a flask app which runs behind gunicorn server that have 3 endpoints</p>
<ul>
<li>[GET] /dc - to receive the PWM duty cycle value.</li>
<li>[POST] /dc - to set the PWM duty cycle value.</li>
<li>[GET] /lux - to receive the lux values from lux sensors plugged in to raspberry pi.</li>
</ul>
<p>And that's all the functionality of the teapot.</p>
<p>Fullmoon can communicate with multiple teapots.
It's being deployed using docker-compose.</p>
<p>It has 3 services</p>
<ul>
<li>app - the logic of the application.
<ul>
<li>records the lux and duty cycle values.</li>
<li>can call the 3 end points of teapot.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>postgre - relational database to store the recorded values.</li>
<li>admineer - front end for the database.</li>
</ul>
<p>That's it for the base system.</p>
<p>I hope, with the time fullmoon will be grow into be really smart and teapot will get better with doing what's being asked.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>[book]Commodore Hornblower</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-08-10-[book]Commodore-Hornblower/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Hornblower sails to Baltic with now Captain bush and few of ships under his command to persuade Russians to support England and fight with French.
Which he manages to do well.
Then he stays there to support the war against French.
At the end they get news that French got defeated near Moscow.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>[book]Flying Colours</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-08-10-[book]Flying-Colours/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>This is the story of Hornblower's escape from French prison.
With the support from Mr.Brown, a sailor captured with him and now one leg less Mr. Bush, his first lieutenant.</p>
<p>They make their escape on the way to meet Napoleon (and most possibly their death).
On the way to Napoleon the coach they are carrying get in to accident and after knocking down the French officer who's responsible for them they jumped in to a boat and goes down a river.
But in the middle of the journey they got thrown down in a waterfall.</p>
<p>But a good Frenchman comes in to their aid and provide cover for them until Bush recovers, weather gets better and a boat being built.
In the mean time Hornblower manages to seduce the widowed daughter in law of the Frenchman.</p>
<p>After few months time they successfully ride the boat to sea and captures a British ship caught by French and set sail to England.
Once they got in to England, Hornblower gets to know his wife died on child birth and he's now a father.
In addition Barbara got widowed and she's looking after his son now.
Also Hornblower gets promoted to Commodore.</p>
<p>Hornblower marries Barbara(can't remember it's exactly on this book, but it's definitely before the next book) and all the things workout well for the hero.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>[book]Ship of the Line</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-08-10-[book]Ship-of-the-Line/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Hornblower gets a ship of the line in a fleat who's supposed to provide protection for a bunch of merchant fleats.
As it happens the admiral of the fleat is newly married Barbara's husband.
He's still torn betwean feelings to Barbara(who he met on his previous journey and offered him her love) and his now pregnant wife.</p>
<p>He also gets the command of a bigger ship HMS Sutherland.
But he's short of people to work on the ship.</p>
<p>Anyway he set's sail and at the end after a battle with 4 French ships gets captured by French.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>[book]Happy Return</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-07-23-[book]Happy-Return/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>After reading most of the books in Terry Prachet's Disc world series,
I started reading a new series.
It's written by C.S. Foster and about a sea man named Horatio Hornblower</p>
<p>After reading the Disc world series in chronological order,
I decided to read this in the order author written it.
I feel it helps in getting the little details and necessary character introductions.</p>
<p>This story happens in real world (unlike disc world series).</p>
<p>This book introduces us to Horatio Hornblower and his crew.
Horatio is the captain of a English navy ship named Lydia.
This is the time when Britain rule the sea.
They fight other nations to retain that power.</p>
<p>Horatio first tasked with helping a insane Spanish land owner to rebel against the Spanish government.
Goal is to weaken the Spanish power.
But then politics change and Spain become ally of Britain.
Now he finds himself with orders to help the Spanish government and fight the Spanish rebel he first helped with.
Which he does successfully and also gives passage to a lady in a powerful family (Lady Barbara)</p>
<p>Though he's a married man He fell in love with Lady Barbara and she with him.
But he fights his feelings and manged to stay faithful to his wife.</p>
<p>At the end the ship reaches England successfully and Lady Barbara leaves little crossed and heart broken and Horatio questioning his decisions.</p>
<p>Most interesting part of the book is to me is the narrative of the inner thoughts of the Horatio.
Though he's the captain of the ship and his crew respects him very much,
He doesn't keep himself in high standards.
He questions his decisions.
He's under confidant but he doesn't show that to outside.
He goes into deep struggle to hide his feelings.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/happy_return.jpg" alt="" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>[book]Unseen Academicals</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-07-06-[book]Unseen-Academicals/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>This book is mainly about football.
In Ankh-Morpork, football is a wild game played on streets with violence.
Vetinary(ruler of Anch-Morpork) wants to tame football.
So he organizes a football tournament and ask the archchancellor of Unseen University(University of wizards) to participate in it.
Wizards make a team with librarian(happens to be a ape due to magic spell gone wrong) as the goal keeper.
And eventually Mister Nutt get to be the coach plus substitute of the team.</p>
<p>Mister Nutt happens to be a orc.
General opinion is orcs are bad.
They tear off limbs of living humans.
Orcs are now thought to be extinct.
But Mister Nutt is well read nice orc, whom the extinction is yet to happen.
And his main job is to dribble candles at the Unseen University.</p>
<p>But the mobs who were the main part of the old football are trying to bring violence to new football.</p>
<p><em>“Juliet’s version of cleanliness was next to godliness, which was to say it was erratic, past all understanding and was seldom seen.”</em></p>
<p><img src="/assets/unseen_academicals.jpg" alt="" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fried Rice</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-06-28-Fried-Rice/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Today I made fried rice from left over rice and chicken.
The taste of this varient is more similar to fried rice found in small shops.</p>
<p>The final result look like this,</p>
<p><img src="/assets/fried_rice.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Ingredients :</p>
<ul>
<li>Left over rice collected over about a week and stored in fridge,
(storing in the fridge adds a nice texture to the rice)</li>
<li>2 Carrots - cut in to thin pieces.</li>
<li>3 Leaks - cut in to small pieces.(doesn't add much taste, but looks great)</li>
<li>3 Red onions - cut in to small pieces.</li>
<li>3 garlic pieces - same as red onions but smaller.</li>
<li>small piece of ginger - chopped in to small pieces.</li>
<li>4 eggs</li>
<li>left over bite chicken - microwave and peel in to thin pieces.</li>
<li>piece of butter.</li>
<li>Salt and pepper.</li>
</ul>
<p>Process:</p>
<ul>
<li>Once ingredients are prepared,
Heat the wok.</li>
<li>Add butter and let it melt.</li>
<li>Add garlic.</li>
<li>Heat until garlic become kind of golden brown.</li>
<li>Add red onion.</li>
<li>When onions changed the color to golden brown add carrot.</li>
<li>Add salt and pepper to the taste.</li>
<li>Heat until carrot is half cooked.</li>
<li>Make space in the middle of the wok and put the contents of eggs there.</li>
<li>Mix the stuff in the wok well.</li>
<li>Heat it until the eggs become tiny solid pieces.</li>
<li>Add chicken pieces and leaks to the mix at this point.</li>
<li>Mix it well.</li>
<li>Add rice.</li>
<li>increase the heat.</li>
<li>Keep mixing it until you hear noise of kind of tiny explosions of the rice.</li>
</ul>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>[book]The Last Hero</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-06-26-[book]The-Last-Hero/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Cohen(old legendary barbarian hero) with his silver horde is going to meet the gods and return what first hero stole(fire).</p>
<p>And state his dislike on heroes dying from natural causes.</p>
<p>Then may be blow up where the gods live.</p>
<p>But if they are successful the world will end.</p>
<p>So Rincewind(best unsuccessful wizard, accidental savior of world(multiple times), but most of all a coward),
watchman Carrot(6 foot tall honest dwarf policeman) and Leonard of Quirm(absent minded genius) are going to stop them on orders from Lord Vetinari(patricain/dictator of the city state Ankh-Mprpork).</p>
<p><em>“Lots of people would be as cowardly as me if they were brave enough.”</em> - RinceWind</p>
<p><img src="/assets/last_hero.jpg" alt="" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stats for Half Month of Running</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-06-22-Stats-for-Half-Month-of-Running/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I started recording my runs on a app called strava in June 5th.
Today is June 22nd,
So I have data for 16 days(until yesterday) of running.
Half a month of data.
So I decided to see how I have being doing.</p>
<p>But before that a bit about my run recording mechanism.
I am learning to run using a book written by a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_Daniels_(coach)">Jack Daniels</a>.
It has workouts on different paces per session.
And I record them different paces as different runs.
(To see the pace difference)</p>
<p>Bellow are the numbers as of now.</p>
<ul>
<li>400m best :1.52(4.40/km)</li>
<li>1/2 mile best :4.35(5.42/km)</li>
<li>1k best :5.45</li>
<li>1mile best :10.09(6.18/km)</li>
<li>2mile best :21.33(6.42/km)</li>
<li>longest run :5.54km(7.15/km)</li>
<li>total distance :60km</li>
<li>total time :7.11</li>
</ul>
<p>And this is the route (which roughly translates to 1.1km).</p>
<p><img src="/assets/pungol_park_route.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>I also want to note that I'm not deliberately trying to set the records (yet).
Still only trying to follow the plan in the book.
So above numbers are not an end itself but a mean to an end.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>First Attempt at Running</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-06-18-First-Attempt-at-Running/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>First time I remember running for exercise is when I was in university.
I was either in 3rd or 4th year.
This is either 2014 or 2015, Because I graduated in early 2016.</p>
<p>Got up early morning one day and went for a run.
The reason I remember this event is because of a dog.
With Adjectives like big and vicious looking.</p>
<p>I started the run around 4 am.
I have to get ready and leave for university later that day.
I usually get the 6.13 office train to go to university.
It's about a two hour journey to the university from my home.
Just in time for the morning lecture.</p>
<p>So back to running.
I was going in a steady pace and just passing the 3rd bus halt.
Suddenly I heard a low growl.</p>
<p>When a dog is interested in you in a bad way, first thing to do is stop.
If you run it will definitely chase you.
And dogs can run pretty fast too.</p>
<p>So I stopped.
There was a huge, vicious looking dog snarling at me.
Standing in front of a closed shop.
Most probably it's home.</p>
<p>I tried moving away a bit, slowly.
Growling increased.
I stopped.</p>
<p>There was nobody in the vicinity either.
It was still around 4.30 I think.
World is still sound asleep.
And I was stuck with staring match with a dog.</p>
<p>This went around for about 30 minutes.
Around 5am the road became gradually alive and dog lost the interest me.
Only then I was able to walk away.</p>
<p>And I lost the interest in running for a long time.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Smart AC Part1</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-06-15-Smart-AC-Part1/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Imagine you have a Air Conditioner unit that you don't have to adjust.
You don't need to turn it on or off.
No need to change the mode or adjust the temperature.
It just works.
It predicts your schedule, analyse the current situation and activates the optimum settings.</p>
<p>I was thinking about making one since I tried to make a IR remote to control and RF device. You can read about it from <a href="https://kasungamlath.com/blog/Raspberry-Pi-Universal-Remote/">here</a>.</p>
<p>To give some context,
In my room I have a fairly common HITACHI Air Conditioner unit.
It has a IR interface.
I also have a Raspberry Pi device at home.
And 2 sets of IR receiver + IR emitter units from an early failed experiment.</p>
<p>So I made an high level plan.</p>
<ol>
<li>Make a programmable interface to control the AC.</li>
<li>Make a smart system to decide the optimum settings for the room.</li>
<li>Integrate both and enjoy a smart AC.</li>
</ol>
<p>And set on to work.</p>
<p>First I configured the raspberry pi device and plugged in the IR receiver and IR emitter in to 2 GPIO pins.
Then started up the <a href="http://abyz.me.uk/rpi/pigpio/piscope.html">PISCOPE</a>(It let you analyse the voltage changes on GPIO pins).
Once the set up is in place, pointed the AC remote to raspberry pi conneccted IR receiver plugged in to raspberry pi and pushed few buttons.
As expected PISCOPE showed the changes in the voltage for corresponding GPIO pin.</p>
<p>I'll need to record the original remote signals (from AC remote controller) in order to play them back via raspberry pi connected IR emitter.
So looked up on internet for a way to decode the IR signals.</p>
<p>Almost all the articles I found uses LIRC module to record and playback IR signals.
So I configured the LIRC module in raspberry pi device and tried again.
LIRC comes with multiple tools.</p>
<ul>
<li>mode2 - shows up the time which corresponds to 1s and 0s of the recieved signal.</li>
<li>irrecode - recode the receiving IR signal</li>
<li>irsend - playback a received IR signal</li>
</ul>
<p>The mode2 worked as expected but I couldn't get the irrecode to work.
Most probably because they changed the lirc kernel module in the latest kernel and tools are not caught up with it yet.</p>
<p>I tried to make it work trying various solutions listed on various articles with no luck.</p>
<p>OK.
Time for a change in the attack.</p>
<p>Since the PISCOPE tool I was using is capable of showing up the signal,
and it comes with a library called pigpio I should be able to leverage that and manually recode the signal right?</p>
<p>So I started going through the documentation of pigpio. (by now I had some experience in using the library because I already used it to <a href="https://kasungamlath.com/blog/Adjusting-LED-brightnes-with-PWM/">control a LED brightness</a>.
As it happens, in the examples sections it already had a script to record and playback IR signals.
So while thanking the person who wrote that library plus the script, I downloaded the script and tried on my raspberry pi.</p>
<p>It worked!!!</p>
<p>After a while I was able to record the signals from AC remote and play them back to AC unit.
Most of the buttons are mapped to a static signal.</p>
<p>But in the case up and down buttons, they seem to be not static.
Meaning if you press the up button twice, the resulting signals are not the same.
It seems they carry the unit I'm trying to set.
For example,
if I'm increasing the temperature from 25 to 26 by pressing the up button,
it results a signal which contains the number 26.</p>
<p>This is the signal to turn the AC unit on.
The numbers in the signal represent the time(in microseconds) which the volt level stayed same.
For example in this case, it stayed down for 3370 microseconds then up for 1650 microseconds then again 439 microseconds in down state.
(The default volt level is up once after you plugged in the IR receiver).</p>
<pre><code>3370, 1650, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439
</code></pre>
<p>Signal to change the mode to humidity.</p>
<pre><code>3370, 1650, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 413, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439, 1262, 439
</code></pre>
<p>As you can see they are similar in most parts.
They start with 3370, 1650 segment which you don't see within the signal after that.
And contain only 3 distinct time values(439,1262,413) apart from start segment.</p>
<p>By this time I was fairly certain somebody have already decoded this code.
So I set out to find something on it on the internet.
I found this <a href="https://perhof.wordpress.com/2015/03/29/reverse-engineering-hitachi-air-conditioner-infrared-remote-commands/">article</a>.</p>
<p>According to it,</p>
<ul>
<li>3370, 1650, 439 is the header.</li>
<li>1262, 439 segment is binary one.</li>
<li>413, 439 segment is binary zero.</li>
</ul>
<p>Note :These numbers have some error margin.
Since they are in microsecond level when measured they are not in these precious numbers.
They changed bit up and down each time.
But it doesn't matter for the communication.
IR receiver in AC unit is bit forging in this regard.</p>
<p>Article also confirmed my hunch that up and down buttons sends up the number within the signal.
It contains in the byte 14 and 15.
Byte 14 is the number with least significant bit first.
Byte 15 is the inverse of the byte 14.
Byte 15 might be acting as a parity byte for the byte 14.</p>
<p>To confirm if it's the same as in my case,
I decoded the signal to binary representation.</p>
<p>Signal representation for 27c.</p>
<pre><code>3378, 1643, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 397, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442, 1243, 442
</code></pre>
<p>Binary signal</p>
<pre><code>[1, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0], [0, 0, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0, 0], [0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0], [0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 1, 0], [1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 0, 1], [1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1], [0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0], [0, 0, 1, 1, 0, 0, 1, 1], [1, 1, 0, 0, 1, 1, 0, 0], [0, 0, 0, 1, 1, 0, 0, 1], [1, 1, 1, 0, 0, 1, 1, 0], [0, 0, 1, 0, 0, 0, 1, 0], [1, 1, 0, 1, 1, 1, 0, 1], [0, 0, 1, 1, 0, 1, 1, 0], [1, 1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0, 1], [0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0], [1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1], [0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0], [1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1], [0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0], [1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1], [0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0], [1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1], [0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0], [1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1], [1, 0, 1, 0, 1, 0, 0, 0], [0, 1, 0, 1, 0, 1, 1, 1], [1, 0, 0, 0, 1, 0, 1, 1], [0, 1, 1, 1, 0, 1, 0, 0], [0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0], [1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1], [0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0], [1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1]
</code></pre>
<p>Byte 14 and 15</p>
<pre><code>[0,0,1,1,0,1,1,0],[1,1,0,0,1,0,0,1]
</code></pre>
<p>So the byte 14 is really the number 27 with least significant bit first.
And byte 15 is the inverse of byte 14.</p>
<p>And that's it for the mystery of the AC remote.</p>
<p>So now I can generate and transmit all the necessary signal to control the basics of AC unit using only the raspberry pi unit.</p>
<p>Next part will be combining all this and building a programmable interface to emit these signals...</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Almost 5k Run</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-06-09-The-Almost-5k-Run/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I started running systematically last April.
Before that I was running continuously for few months but couldn't feel a improvement.
So I got into thinking even though I was just running for fun why not do that based on a plan and fast track the improvements.</p>
<p>So I started looking for a plan.
I found a nice community dedicated to running in <a href="https://reddit.com/running">reddit</a>.
From the wiki page of that subreddit I found a suggestion for a book.
Book is called Daniel's running formula written by a guy named <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_Daniels_(coach)">Jack Daniels</a></p>
<p>Author's name itself piqued my interest on the book.</p>
<p>So I acquired the book and started reading.
Turns out this guy has a PhD on exercise physiology and have nothing to with whiskey.
He goes into details on stuff about running and people he had trained and mentored.
Overall it's pretty good book, If you want to improve your running.</p>
<p>In the book there is a plan with four stages(among other things).</p>
<ol>
<li>White starting plan.</li>
<li>Red intermediate plan.</li>
<li>Blue advanced plan.</li>
<li>Gold elite plan</li>
</ol>
<p>Each stage have 4 levels each lasting 4 weeks.
So to complete one stage it takes at least 16 weeks.</p>
<p>As I have being running for few months already I started with 3rd level of White starting plan.
Schedule is different for each weekday.
Have to run 3 days per week with at least one restday in between.
In that level longest continues run is 20 min easy pace run.</p>
<p>After 4 weeks I moved up in to 4th level of white starting plan.
Longest run here is a 30 min easy pace run.</p>
<p>After 4 weeks in that plan plus 2 weeks of injury time from kitchen accident and 1 more week of catching up after the recovery,
This week I graduated into Red intermediate plan level 1.</p>
<p>Yesterday was the first day of the plan.
I had a 30 min run segment in the schedule.</p>
<p>By then I had bought a phone pouch and started using strava to track the runs.
Yesterday just before the run I noticed there is a 5k challenge in strava.</p>
<p>Though my usual distance for the 30 min run is like 4.4k I signed up for the challenge.
And ran the usual 4.4k distance in like 28 mins and ran additional 600m to complete the 5k.
Total distance took about 34 minutes(according to my wrist watch).</p>
<p>I finished the run with a sense of satisfaction and checked the stats in the phone.
(since pouch is wrapped in the upper arm, it's not accessible while running)
To my disappointment it had only tracked 4.74k in 32.04 minutes!!!</p>
<p><img src="/assets/run47.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>So either my distance measuring(I measured it in google maps) is wrong or the app has not tracked it correctly.
I'll have to run again and see what happens to be sure.</p>
<p>Either way that's my first attempt at running 5k.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Adjusting LED brightnes with PWM</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-06-08-Adjusting-LED-brightnes-with-PWM/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Following the my adventure with capturing the RF signal with IR sensor,
I had two ways to proceed.
Go back to the shop and buy RF sensor.
But the community cases(covid19) of Singapore is getting high again.
Didn't feel like going out.</p>
<p>Thankfully there is another way to adjust the brightness of a LED.
Pulse width modulation.
I had a hunch that's how the existing light adjustments worked too(via RF remote)
And I already have the necessary circuit items with me.</p>
<p>Adjusting the LED brightness via raspberry pi part 2.</p>
<p>Even though the end goal is to adjust the brightness of LED set with external power source, I set up to adjust the brightness of a single LED powered via raspberry pi GPIO pin it selt.</p>
<p>I configured the new circuit in bread board.
It was just one resistor and one LED connected with jumping wires to GPIO pins.</p>
<p>It worked the first time!!!</p>
<p><video controls><source src="/assets/led_pwm.mp4" type="video/mp4">Your browser does not support the video tag.</video></p>
<p>Now for the complex circuit with external power source.
(One LED is a poor application when come to lighting a room)
Configured the circuit.
Plugged one unit of LEDs we bought early.</p>
<p>And nothing happened!!!
Well I am in a familiar ground again.</p>
<p>Had a hard look at the circuit.
Looked for the pin layouts.
Found out my knowledge of transistors are only valid for some simpler dimension.
It's totally different when it comes to PNP and NPN!!!</p>
<p>Rewired the circuit.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/pwm_ex.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Nope.
Seems the transistor pin layout was not the only issue.</p>
<p>I started the <a href="http://abyz.me.uk/rpi/pigpio/piscope.html">piscope</a>(It gives a live graph of GPIO volt levels)
Well there is a problem there.
It's not showing the volt level changes for the pin which circuit was connected.</p>
<p>I changed the GPIO pin.
Updated the script.
Executed it.</p>
<p>Houston, we have landed!!!</p>
<p>At first configurations I was using software GPIO and it was showing some jitters in the light.
That's because the Linux is not a real time OS and it uses scheduling technique to operate in multi process environment.
So when come to sending signals via GPIO in a high frequency it's possible to miss some due to scheduling.</p>
<p>But the raspberry pi is capable with hardware PWM and i found a nice <a href="http://abyz.me.uk/rpi/pigpio/">library</a> with python interface.
It mentioned there are few GPIO pins which are capable driving hardware PWM.
I tried with GPIO pin 18 and it worked.</p>
<p>With PWM it adjust the brightness by changing the duty cycle(in 50% duty cycle, one half of it is in hight volt state and other half is in low state, 75% is 3/4 in high and 1/4 in low)
Also you can change the frequency. It defines how long is a duty cycle(high+low) in time dimension.</p>
<p>With low frequencies(~sub 100Hz) the blinking is visible to naked eye.
When it increases(~100Hz - 1kHz) it's become invisible to naked eye but can be seen from camera.
This the frequency range being used by the frequency in embedded circuit the LED set came with.</p>
<p>Bellow is a video recording(high frame rate) of the LED brightness being adjusted via circuit it came with.</p>
<p><video controls><source src="/assets/led_blink.mp4" type="video/mp4">Your browser does not support the video tag.</video></p>
<p>But it's possible to further increase(more than 1kHz) the PWM frequency and hide the blinking from even hight frame rate camera captures.
Upper bound for raspberry pi hardware PWM is ~20Mhz.
I checked with a slow mo video from an iPhone SE 2020, with high frequency camera didn't see any blinking.</p>
<p><video controls><source src="/assets/led_no_blink.mp4" type="video/mp4">Your browser does not support the video tag.</video></p>
<p>Well that's it for adjusting the LED brightness with raspberry pi.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Raspberry Pi Universal Remote</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-06-07-Raspberry-Pi-Universal-Remote/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I was working for a Smart light project for a while now.
Goal of this project is to provide optimal brightness for occupancies in a room while saving the energy.
This project is going to be setup in a campus building.
But we still don't have the access to the building infrastructure yet.
So we were setting up a test bed in a campus lab.</p>
<p>Then came covid19.</p>
<p>We had to move to work from home.
To continue the work it's required to adjust the lights in the campus lab from home.
Since we won't have any access to already installed lights in the lab,
we bought were brightness adjustable generic led lights.
Their marketing term was kitchen counter lights.
They came with a remote.
To operate you have to be there in person.</p>
<p>But our requirement is to change the lab lights from home.</p>
<p>We come up with two ideas.</p>
<ol>
<li>Use the existing remote interface of the lights and use a raspberry pi with IR emitter as a trigger.</li>
<li>Use PWM with raspberry pi to control the LED brightness.</li>
</ol>
<p>Since the first idea looked less complex we set out to try it first.
Following it the high level plan.</p>
<ol>
<li>Setup a receiver with raspberry pi.</li>
<li>Recode the signals from the remote to the raspberry pi.</li>
<li>Setup a emitter with raspberry pi.</li>
<li>Replay the signals to lights.</li>
<li>Setup the raspberry pi in the test bed.</li>
</ol>
<p>So I searched about it found some guides.</p>
<p>Well I think I should also mention that,
Last time I did something electronic is like 15 years ago when I made a Knignt Rider circuit.
Which was array of LEDs blinking for the pattern as same as the car(kit) in Knight Rider TV series.
(That circuit was pretty famous those days)</p>
<p>Back to present,
I bought the items required.
<img src="/assets/circuit_items.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Came home plugged them to raspberry pi using bread board.
Configure the software.
(That was more complex than setting up the circuit.)
Pointed the remote to the sensor and pushed few buttons.</p>
<p>Nothing happened!!!
It was supposed to display the signals.</p>
<p>Well It's simple circuit.
An IR receiver plugged in to raspberry pi.</p>
<p>I started digging around and found there was a Kernel update few months ago which replaced the kernel module mentioned in the guide.
Well, that's not too hard to fix.
Downgrade the OS in raspberry pi to a version with early kernel version and start from the beginning.</p>
<p>So I removed the memory card from raspberry pi and flashed it with a early version of OS image.
Inserted the chip to raspberry pi and turned on the power.</p>
<p>Pi refused to boot!!!
Green LED was flashing to a pattern.
As it happened the OS image was too old to work with the device.</p>
<p>Downloaded a fairly new OS image.
Flashed the chip again.
Started the raspberry pi.</p>
<p>It started.
But that's the end of the good news.</p>
<p>I configured the software stack as per the guide.
But still not getting the signals from remote.
And I was stuck now.
Don't know what part is not working.
It could be,</p>
<ol>
<li>Faulty receiver</li>
<li>Faulty wiring</li>
<li>Library not working</li>
<li>Or something completely unrelated.</li>
</ol>
<p>I don't have any experience with these stuff.
Don't know the tools of the trade.</p>
<p>How does one debug these stuff?</p>
<p>Well internet is a wonderful thing.
I found a nice tool called piscope.
It displays a voltages from GPIO pins in a live graph.
So I could use it for eliminate some possible issue candidates.</p>
<p>I downloaded it, build it, installed.</p>
<p>Well no luck.
Graph isn't showing any action.</p>
<p>Now what.
I'm running out of ideas here.</p>
<p>Wait may be it's the remote.
I tried the AC remote.</p>
<p>Voila,
Graph came live.</p>
<p>Well Well Well,
As it turns out I was trying to capture a RF signal from a IR receiver.
(Remote came with a RF remote and I bought a IR sensor.)</p>
<p>I guess now I can make a smart AC...</p>
<p>Bellow are the guides I followed if you are interested,</p>
<p>lirc guide</p>
<p><a href="https://gist.github.com%5B2%5E/prasanthj/c15a5298eb682b%5B2%5Ede34961c322c95378b">https://gist.github.com[2^/prasanthj/c15a5298eb682b[2^de34961c322c95378b</a></p>
<p>hardware guide</p>
<p><a href="https://www.hackster.io/austin-stanton/creating-a-raspberry-pi-universal-remote-with-lirc-2fd581">https://www.hackster.io/austin-stanton/creating-a-raspberry-pi-universal-remote-with-lirc-2fd581</a></p>
<p>lirc guide for strech/buster</p>
<p><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/forums/viewtopic.php?f=28&amp;t=235256">https://www.raspberrypi.org/forums/viewtopic.php?f=28&amp;t=235256</a></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Repairing My Old Android Phone Attempt 01</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-06-04-Repairing-My-Old-Android-Phone-Attempt-01/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>It happened 2 weeks ago.
My phone died.
It was a Xiaomi mi A2.
It suddenly refused to charge.
<a href="https://kasungamlath.com/blog/Phone-Died/">here</a> is the full story.</p>
<p>Apart from the not charging issue (and cracked screen) phone was in good condition.
So I though about fixing it.
As I checked with multiple cables and charging sources(without any luck) I assumed issue is with the phone it self.
Could be either software issue or hardware issue.
But couldn't investigate further as phone is not starting anymore.</p>
<p>But just before dying phone was heating up abnormally while plugged in to rapid charge.
Attributing to this I assumed the most probable fault part is the battery.
So I ordered a Battery which cost ~30 SGD.
It arrived yesterday.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/phone_and_battery.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>So I took the phone apart.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/phone_parts.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>There was a issue when replacing the battery from phone due to glue.
But with some difficulty I managed to remove the battery.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/old_battery.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Installed the new battery and booted up the phone.
Thankfully phone booted up.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/phone_new_battery.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>
<p>Battery had about ~50% of the charge out of the box.
But when plugged in to the charger it still refused to charge.</p>
<p>Well that's life for you.</p>
<p>So to check if it's a software issue I did a hard reset.
Still not charging.</p>
<p>But I noticed a interesting fact.
When plugged in to the PC, only when you rammed the cable up the port it detects the connection.
And it does that with a only one specific cable too.
But unfortunately that connection also keep loosing and reconnecting.</p>
<p>So as per evidence it's a faulty usb port.
I ordered one today for ~10 SGD.
It should arrive within 2 weeks.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thoughts on iPhone</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-06-03-Thoughts-on-iPhone/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>After the death of my previous Android phone, last month I bought an iphone se 2020.
These are my thoughts after 2 weeks of use.</p>
<p>For the perspective my old phone is a xiaomi mi A2 which I bought for 300 SGD and used for 21 months.
New phone did cost 650 SGD.</p>
<p>It's small, and that's a good thing for me.
It fits perfectly in my pocket.
It's really hard to find a good small android phone these days.
Last time I checked closest thing I found was google pixel4.</p>
<p>Though this model has a bit small battery I get about 2 days of battery life.
About same I got from the old phone.
The earpods it shipped with, sounds good.
I remember hearing some static noise (in varying levels) in all the phone + earphones combos I previously owned.
In this phone + earpods, there isn't any static noise.
Also my bluetooth headset pairs with the phone with no hassle.
(It used to give trouble with my previous phone).
Cellular + wifi Reception is also pretty good.
I used to get disconnected from home wifi in some parts of my room with the old phone.
But new phone doesn't have any such issues.
Also it doesn't heat up while when in call or when charging like old phone did.</p>
<p>When compared the cost of the phone per month, old phone did cost 300SGD/21 = 14.286SGD per month.
So if I'll be able to use this phone for 650SGD / 14.286SGD = 45 months(4 years minus 3 months) new phone is cheaper compared to old phone.
When considering there are still iphone 6 models (released in 6 years ago) which got the latest ios update, I think it's a fairly reasonable expectation.</p>
<p>All in all I'm pretty happy with the new phone.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>DIY vpn Server</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-06-01-DIY-vpn-Server/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I'm using <a href="https://www.vultr.com/">vultr</a> as the provider for the vpn server host.
(But it's possible to choose any VPS provider)
Bellow are the steps I follow to create the vpn server.</p>
<ol>
<li>Build a virtual private server.(I'm using 3.50 USD/month configuration)</li>
<li>Install ubuntu 18.04 on it.</li>
<li>Once installation is finished ssh in to the server.</li>
<li>Clone<a href="https://github.com/trailofbits/algo">algo</a> to the home directory in the server.</li>
<li>Follow the installtion guide on repository.</li>
<li>Once installation is done copy the config files to all the devices.</li>
</ol>
<p>Monthly VPN bandwidth capped at host configuration bandwidth devided by two.
(In my configuration it's 500GB/2 = 250GB).</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>My Latest Laptop</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-05-30-My-Latest-Laptop/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>First of all I bought this about a year ago.</p>
<p>I have 3 working laptops(and one not working).</p>
<ul>
<li>thinkpad x220 - daily driver</li>
<li>thinkpad x230 - backup laptop</li>
<li>thinkpad x200 - home media server</li>
</ul>
<p>Among them x200 is the latest acquisition.
This is how I got it.</p>
<p>One day I was browsing the carousel(online platform to sell new/used goods in Singapore).
There was a listing of a thinkpad x200 for 20 SGD.
To give some background this model is released for 1k+USD on year 2008.
Here on 2020 it's on sale for 20SGD.
As I was already the proud owner of 2 thinkpads, I knew the great build quality of these models.
Description said it was not turning on.
But for 20SGD I thought it's worth a try.</p>
<p>So I contacted the seller.
He offered to come to the Basement of SMU(Where I work).
So we arranged a date for the sale.</p>
<p>On that date I went to the arranged meeting place.
With a friend who was intrigued by this idea of 20S$ laptop.
As promised the seller came on time.
He was a nice young guy.
Want to get rid of faulty laptop he got for most probably sub 20S$.
Or may be it was a family heirloom.</p>
<p>I paid him 20S$ and got the laptop.
He wanted to know what I'm planning to do with it.
I was hoping to get it working after a thorough cleaning.
But I didn't want to tell that and make him feel he got the wrong end of the bargain.
So I told him a lie.
I told him I already owned another non working laptop of the same model and hoping build working one combining parts from both.
(That was actually my backup plan).
So we parted ways feeling both got richer.</p>
<p>I came home and disassembled the laptop.
It required only one philips screw drive to take it all apart.
And to my utter dismay the mother board had a burn mark and seemed fried.
Infact after reassembling it didn't work.
That puts end to my 20S$ laptop dream.</p>
<p>Now as for the backup plan, I started looking for a x200 motherboard.
No luck.
But there was a another unit(working one this time) with a yellowing screen and Japanese keyboard layout for 90S$ on carousel.
I only wanted a motherboard.
But I was pretty sure this guy won't sell me only the Motherboard.
If he do he'll end up in the same place as me.
So I contacted him and offered to buy the laptop minus hard disk and RAM for 50S$.
Both he can sell separately with ease.
He agreed.</p>
<p>We met.
I checked the device.
Removed the ram+hard disk.
Payed the guy.
Brought the devise home.</p>
<p>On the following weekend I disassembled both devices.
Cleaned all the parts.
Put the Mother board from 2nd unit in the first one.
And voila, I ended up with one working and one not working laptops for 70S$.</p>
<p>It's battery life was pretty bad.
Best battery from both devices only holds for ~30min.
So I plugged my external hard disk in to it and configured it as a wireless home media server.
To this date(It's about a year now since the operaion) it happily serves media to me.
Not a bad place to end up for a 12 year laptop IMO.</p>
<p>That's the story of my latest laptop.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/x200.jpg" alt="full-width" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rationale Behind Brightness Module</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-05-29-Rationale-Behind-Brightness-Module/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>The research project I'm working on these days is suppose to make a building smart.
It should know it's occupants whereabouts and have to adjust energy related parameters(light level, AC level, etc) accordingly.
For example if there are 3 people occupying a 1 desk in a big room with 25 desks, it should keep lights in workable level only around the occupied desk.
The ultimate goal is reducing the energy consumption while keeping occupants happy.</p>
<p>In order to optimally adjust the lights building should also have a sense of the brightness of the affecting area.
Else there a chance to wrongfully adjust the lights and be a dumb building.</p>
<p>We already have a dockerized system to detect the occupancy of the building.
And we have promising results for the brightness detection too(fingers crossed).
So I am designing a new docker service to integrate this brightness detection to that existing system.</p>
<p>The responsibilities of the module are,</p>
<ol>
<li>access each cameras feed</li>
<li>detect the brightness of each scene</li>
<li>write that values to a database.</li>
</ol>
<p>Then another service will read this brightness value and the occupancy values(output of another module) and adjust the buildings AC and lights.</p>
<p>To do this first we have to access the camera feed.
There are about 50 cameras in the building.
We are using opencv library VidoeCapture method for that.
Since it's a blocking call and a expensive at that, module will have one thread to decode each camera feed.
Then since detection of brightness is also comparatively a expensive operation there will be one brightness calculating thread for each camera.
All this calculated brightness values will go for a single queue and a single database thread will write all these values to DB.</p>
<p>That's the design at the start and based on metrics it will be adjusted.
After all <em>premature optimization is the root of all evil</em>.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wifi Localization</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-05-28-Wifi-Localization/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Wifi localization work more or less like localization with GPS.
Instead of GPS satellites it uses wifi access points.
Instead of GPS receivers it uses wifi modules(is found on any device with wifi).</p>
<p>Wifi access points can get a measurement for signal strength of the device relative the access point.
These measurements are read periodically for each device.
It's supposed to help with the quality control.
Lower the signal strength harder it becomes to communicate with the device.
So it's required to measure the load the access point is working on.
Once it passes certain threshold quality control can kicks in make necessary decisions like kicking out far out devices, stop accepting new devices and such.
These measurements can be accessed from a central location.</p>
<p>This signal strength has a relationship with the distance.
It requires at least 3 access points to successfully determine a location of a wifi module.
So once it find where the device is in a signal strength space it can be converted to spatial space.</p>
<p>But of course once it detects a location, it's relative to wifi access point network.
It doesn't have mush application value.
It needs to be converted to a real world location.
The particular implementation I've worked with has a fingerprinting phase to achieve this.</p>
<p>In the beginning it marks up bunch of landmarks to cover the area where the localization needs to be done.
Then for all these landmarks, using number of (in the same build/model) devices it measures the signal strength relative to each access points it can reach it to.
This is possible since from the central location all the access point signal measurements can be accessed and they carry the device Wifi MAC address with each these signal measurement.
Once this is completed a fingerprint map is said to be built.</p>
<p>Now it's possible to find the device locations compared to the used landmarks.
At the central location it builds another signal strength map to each device which is visible to wifi network.
Then using the previously built fingerprint map it finds the nearest land mark for each of them.Thus it can approximately say where the each device is.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>My Laptop</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-05-27-My-Laptop/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>My personal laptop is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ThinkPad_X_series#X220">Thinkpad x220</a>
It was released on 2011 April with starting <a href="https://www.laptopmag.com/reviews/laptops/lenovo-thinkpad-x220">price</a> of</p>
<ul>
<li>i3 - 979 USD</li>
<li>i5 - 1299 USD</li>
<li>i7 - ???</li>
</ul>
<p>I bought i7 unit second hand on 2018 for about 200SGD
This unit came with,</p>
<ul>
<li>IPS display.</li>
<li>4 gigs of memory.</li>
<li>No hard disk.</li>
<li>6 cell battery with ~35% of design capacity.(which holds up like 2 hours of battery time)</li>
</ul>
<p>I made following upgrades after buying it.</p>
<ul>
<li>2x8GB memory (bought for 60SGD second hand).</li>
<li>Original Lenovo 9 cell battery (bought brand new for ~80SGD).</li>
<li>Samsung 860 EVO 250GB ssd disk (~80SGD).</li>
<li>New thermal paste.</li>
</ul>
<p>So the final specs of the laptop are</p>
<ul>
<li>Intel core i7 second gen processor</li>
<li>16 GB RAM</li>
<li>9 cell battery (about 10 hours of battery life)</li>
<li>250 SSD</li>
<li>12.5 IPS display</li>
</ul>
<p>I'm running a arch linux installation with i3 window manager.
i3 fits perfectly for the 12.5 display.
It's very reliable. I've kept it on for months without any issues.
Main reason for this being the my main laptop (I have total of 3 working + 1 dead laptops) is the keyboard design.
It's such a pleasure to type on this.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/laptop.jpg" alt="camera-photo" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Trying to Get Raw Accelerometer Data form MiBand3</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-05-26-Trying-to-Get-Raw-Accelerometer-Data-form-MiBand3/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>As I have being running more frequently now I felt a need to log those runs.
So I could see the progress.
My plan was to record the acceleration through out the running session and since it enables to see speed variations.
But to record the acceleration I need to carry a accelerometer on the run.
I'm hesitant to carry a mobile phone because it felts a hindrance to running.</p>
<p>I burrowed a MiBand3 from a friend and gave it a try last weekend.
Problem was via the official app it only outputs the step count.
Band uses the accelerometer data and produces the step count.
I found a <a href="https://medium.com/machine-learning-world/how-i-hacked-xiaomi-miband-2-to-control-it-from-linux-a5bd2f36d3ad">blog post</a> (with the link to source code) about the getting the raw accelerometer data(real time) from a MiBand2.
I setup the project and following another <a href="https://medium.com/@yogeshojha/i-hacked-xiaomi-miband-3-and-here-is-how-i-did-it-43d68c272391">blog post</a> changed the authentication steps and managed to connect to MiBand3 from a rapberry pi.
But unfortunately the mentioned raw accelerometer data retrieval part didn't work for the MiBand3.
I could only get the step count and the heart rate from the band to raspberry pi.</p>
<p>I looked for some other bands on the internet with the access to raw accelerometer data but couldn't find any.
It seems in order to get a wearable device which produces the raw data I'll have to buy a at least midrange smart watch.</p>
<p>Or find a way to change the firmware of miband to store+return raw accelerometer data...</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>New Phone</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-05-22-New-Phone/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>After the death of my previous phone I ordered a new phone.
Due to frustration on android update system(IMO my last phone died because of a buggy OS update) and because apple just released a small budget iPhone with latest bionic ship(emphasized because guarantee on long term software updates) I ordered the iPhone SE 2020.
Because of the current situation(partial lock down due to covid19) ordering via online was the only option.
I ordered it on May 19th.
Apple guaranteed 3-5 business days delivery.
Phone arrived on 2 days later May 21st.
It costs 649 SGD.
While the us price is 400 USD roughly equal to 550 SGD.</p>
<p>I ordered the product red because I liked the red and black color combination.
It was nice built with a small foot print.</p>
<p>This is the first time I'm using an iPhone.
On the first look it seems the software is kind of lagging behind when compared to android.
But what's already there, it works perfect(with contrast to android at some points).</p>
<p>The oldest iPhone to receive the latest latest ios update (13.5) few weeks ago is iPhone 6s which released on 2015.
So I guess 5 year software updates for this phone is not an unreasonable expectation.</p>
<p>The three days that I didn't have a mobile phone made me recognize how much I was dependent on a mobile phone.
From bank digital token to getting the time I was depending on the phone.
First thing I wake up I reach for the phone.
This is while I'm not even on any social media except Linkedin and Whatsapp.
For me it's scary.
I'm planning to gradually cut down this dependency.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>My First Contribution to Firefox</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-05-21-My-First-Contribution-to-Firefox/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>My fist code contribution to Mozilla Firefox got accepted.
It's just fixing a code analysis bug.(and fixing another code analysis warning which caused by the fix).
Anyways it feels good.
I have being using the Firefox since I started using a PC.
Since somewhere around 2007.
So It's good to finally give back.</p>
<p>There are multiple guides on how to make the first contribution.
This is what I followed <a href="https://firefox-source-docs.mozilla.org/contributing/how_to_contribute_firefox.html">https://firefox-source-docs.mozilla.org/contributing/how_to_contribute_firefox.html</a>.
To find the bug I used <a href="https://codetribute.mozilla.org/">https://codetribute.mozilla.org/</a>.</p>
<p>This is the issue on Bugzilla <a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1626754">https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1626754</a>.
This is the issue on Phabricator <a href="https://phabricator.services.mozilla.com/D75704">https://phabricator.services.mozilla.com/D75704</a>.</p>
<p>It's scheduled to go live with version 78 !!!</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Phone Died</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-05-20-Phone-Died/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>My phone is a Xiaomi mi A2.
I Specially bought this model because I was in love with google those days and this model was a android one phone.
It guaranteed 2 years of software updates(from google at that time).
So at the cost of 300SGD it was a no brainer.
I bought it on 2018 August after the death of previous phone.</p>
<p>It's display got cracked around 2018 November when I had a running accident.
Never got around to replace the screen.</p>
<p>Day before yesterday(2020 May 18) it stopped charging.
It was having troubles with charging for some time.
When I plugged it in to fast charging it charged slowly.
while getting unusualy heated.
That might be the reason for death.
Interesting thing is it started having these issues after April security update.
Internet is saying that my phone isn't alone in this case.
Lots of people having charging issues after that security update.
Since xiaomi is responsible for those updates(Not google as promised early) they might be to be blamed.</p>
<p>Now it lays in my camera drybox awaiting a chance at revival.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Detecting luminance level of a room using CCTV camera feed</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-03-25-Detecting-luminance-level-of-a-room-using-CCTV-camera-feed/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p><strong>NOTE :Work in Progress</strong></p>
<p>Recently I started working on a new research project.
Goal of this project is to find a relationship between luminance value and RGB value.
The application of the project is to find the luminance level in a in a small room using CCTV camera feed and adjust it to a optimum level.</p>
<p>Bellow is a outline of the plan,</p>
<ol>
<li>Find the background part of the scene.</li>
<li>Segment the image.</li>
<li>Find out suitable segments to keep a pixel value -&gt; illuminance level mapping.</li>
<li>Collect illuminance level(lux value)+images for period of time for above found out patches.</li>
<li>Analize the relationship between the lux values and pixel values.</li>
<li>Train a model using pixel values annotated with lux values to get lux value for new pixel values.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Find the background part of the scene</h3>
<p>To find the background part, used the <a href="https://docs.opencv.org/master/d1/dc5/tutorial_background_subtraction.html">opencv implementation of MOG2</a> method.
This implementation is focused on finding the foreground using a sequece of images.
But it can be easily modified to get the background.
Simply calculating the <code>NOT</code> of the foreground mask got the background mask.</p>
<h3>Segment the image</h3>
<p>In this case it was possible to leverage the fact that the target envirenment is known beforehand.
So it's possible to pick ceratain colors of the background objects.
Then we convert the rgb image to hsv color space and segment the image based on above picked colors.</p>
<h3>Find out suitable segments to keep a pixel value -&gt; illuminance level mapping.</h3>
<p>Using the segmented and filtered image, manually picked a regions of interest to calculate the pixel values.</p>
<h3>Collect illuminance level(lux value)+images for period of time for above found out patches.</h3>
<p>At this phase placed lux meters on the previosly picked regions of interest and collect images from the CCTV camera.</p>
<h3>Analize the relationship between the lux values and pixel values.</h3>
<p>Here calculate the pixel values of captured images and compare them against the collected lux values.</p>
<h3>Train a model using pixel values annotated with lux values to get lux value for new pixel values</h3>
<p>Finally build a model using lux+pixel values collected in previous stages to get the lux values for new pixel values.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>On Automating a Lux Meter Reading</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2020-03-25-On-Automating-a-Lux-Meter-Reading/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>A requirement came up for a project I've been working on recently to continuosly collect lux values+images on certain surfaces.
Since the data collection needed to be done for a considerable time period manual collection was not feasible.
To automate the collection of lux values, bellow ideas were considered.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Use the mobile phone lux meters, do a mapping from those numbers to actual lux meter numbers.
<em>Requires writing/ finding app to collect the lux values periodically.
Don't know about the accuracy of lux meter in mobile phone.
Need to align that values to pictures from ip cam.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Place the lux meters so the ip cam see the display clearly, and read them from image using ocr.
<em>This is the ideal since no need to maintain an alignment form ip cam image to seperate lux reading.
Unfortunately the ip cam resolution is not enough to read the lux meter display clearly.
Even ip cam is zoomed in it's not reliable(and if you zoom in you loose scenario data).</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Setup a mobile phone near to lux meter so it can get a picture. and do ocr on it.
<em>Still need to align 2 images( ip cam and moble phone cam).
Need a mechanism to set up the mobile phone next to lux meter.
Anyway among the optons we have this is the most feasible so far.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Buy lux meters with transmitting feature.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>After doing a feasibilty study decided to go with option 3.</p>
<p>First placed the mobile device slightly above the lux meter display.
Then installed an ip-cam app in the mobile device to make the data collection easier.
To sync up the images(in time dimenssion) used the time stamps stamped by ip cam and mobile app.
Synced up the time in ip-cam and mobile device to same time.
Then using an ocr script read the ocr value from image and anotated the ip-cam image.
To read the images first tried tesseract.
But found out it's more suitable to read the printed stuff(our lux meter has seven segment display digits).
Then we found a way which utilized a mechanism based on contrasting area coordinates. after few tweakings it gave us right readings.</p>
<h3>Results</h3>
<p>input image
<img src="/assets/mobile_ip_cam_lux_reading.jpg" alt="" />
lux reading
<img src="/assets/annotated_lux_reading.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>Unfortunately this setup in neither portable nor scalable.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How To Make Site Like This</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2019-12-09-How-To-Make-Site-Like-This/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>After using Jekyll for some time(about 4 years) and writing occasional posts recently I decided to try something new.
The situation with static site generators seems to be improved a lot since I first tried it. Static sites popularity has being risen and there are lots of site generators with lots of bells and whistles too. But this time I decided to go with a simplest site generator I could find.</p>
<p>I found one which was written in python. It's named <a href="https://github.com/sunainapai/makesite">makesite</a> and has about 1.2k stars on Github.
I forked the repo and made few changes. Mainly to support the Photo post layouts.(I picked up photography as a serious hobby few months ago)
It does what i need and nothing more. And more importantly I know exactly what goes under when come to generating it. So it's totally customizable to my needs if they change in the future.</p>
<p>Now I have my personal space with a simpler design.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Trainbuddy relaunched</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2018-07-14-Trainbuddy-relaunched/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I started working on train buddy app when I was 3rd year undergraduate. I first released it somewhere in 2015 and did a blog post. Actually it's the first post in this blog. So in a way tain buddy is the reason for the inception of this blog. It was a wonderful feeling. Releasing an own work so whole world can see and use. This app made and great conversation topic in interviews. Because I could speak so much about this app. I had so many plans, improvements, features for this app.</p>
<p>It first released as an schedule app. My ultimate goal for this app is to monitor the train locations in real time. Plan was to get the train location from app users themselves. For that I needed an user base. First release was meant to get users. And it did that well too. I had about 1000 users in less than a year I think. Then I added the location tracking features to enable the Train Map. But it didn't go well, most probably I failed to engage users to use it. So it didn't work as I expected. Then I ended reading for the degree and started full time working. (I believe this app played a big part getting me my first job, because in the interview for most of time I did was discuss about this app)</p>
<p>so I got a full time job and didn't have much time to work on the app. Then the back-end service I used got discontinued. You may too remember about Parse(a facebook service). I didn't have time to port the app to another backend so I removed the train map feature(nobody used that in that either). So the train schedule app worked fine for some time. Then the API I used(provided by ICTA) closed the open access. So the schedule function stopped working too. That was the reason for app saying you are not connected to internet even though you are connected. Because it couldn't communicate with the API.</p>
<p>So in today's release I stripped all the schedule features and brought back the train map features. I hope to gradually increase the user base and make this service stable by the time. Today's release is the first step in that direction.</p>
<p>For all the users who's being with the app for some 3+ years Thank you! It won't be possible to come this far without you.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>TrainBuddy 2</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2017-07-01-TrainBuddy-2/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>After more than two years, today I released a new version of TrainBuddy (TrainBuddy acted as my ultimate portfolio app to land current job). New version contains lesser features (features that were broke for some time, but no one complained about. So I guess no one is using them anyway) Now its a full time train schedule app with a brand new API coming in near future. It also contains adds, which I hope will act as a motivating factor for me to tend the app in the future.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>From being an Undergraduate to Software Engineer</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2016-02-13-From-being-an-Undergraduate-to-Software-Engineer/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>I completed the final exams of my B.Sc degree in last month(2016 Jan) and was lucky enough to start working as a Software Engineer from the begining of this month(2016 Feb).</p>
<p>The new working place (Millennium IT's campus) has a nice setup (see <a href="http://www.millenniumit.com/millenniumit-malabe-campus">here</a>) and from my limited experience is full of nice people. So far the only thing I missed from undergraduate life is skipping lectures and the chats we had while having tea with friend who aren't here at Millenium IT.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Big Bad Stupid Facebook</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2015-11-21-Big-Bad-Stupid-Facebook/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>If the Facebook knows your mobile number, know that regardless of your privacy setting it's accessible to virtually anyone.</p>
<p>To check this vulnerability for yourself go to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/login/identify">Facebook account recovery page</a> and try entering some of your friends' mobile numbers in username field. If they had entered their number to the Facebook, you'll get a response with your friend's profile picture and name. And this process can be easily automated using commonly available tools. As for the safety mechanisms, the only one seem to be implemented is IP address blacklisting after about 100-150 tries. This can also be easily bypassed by using a botnet or if your ISP provides dynamic IP addresses, by simply disconnecting and reconnecting to the network. I was able to write a script which check 10,000 numbers well within an hour.</p>
<p>Within the 10,000 numbers I checked, I found about 1,200 numbers are already entered in Facebook.(I checked all the numbers in a random 10,000 range) So it's just a matter of days to collect the mobile numbers of all users of a given network.</p>
<p>Apparently this is a feature(not a bug) of Facebook which suppose to help the users to recover there user accounts. But because of the poorly implemented safety mechanisms an attacker can easily abuse this feature to map mobile numbers with user profiles and do a target attack on a specific person. For example this could easily pave the path for a successful Voice phishing attack - more effective because the computer user is not aware of the fact that his phone number may have ended up in the wrong hands. Just imagine that the crooks call your mobile and address you by your full name and back up their statements with information about you taken straight from your [Facebook] profile.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>TrainBuddy TrainMap Beta</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2015-09-12-TrainBuddy-TrainMap-Beta/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>After being in alpha state for about a month Train Buddy v2 (with TrainMap) is moving to beta today.</p>
<p>For those who didn't know what's the TrainMap is, your initial guess is correct. It's a map of trains (in Srilanka). The way it work is, it gets the status data from application users (only when they allow) in the train and share it with all other users (To share the status data the location and mobile data has to be turned on in the device). Since the status (location/speed) of users in train being same with the status of the train, all the users now have a real-time map of trains.</p>
<p>There are few changes (since alpha) worth mentioning.</p>
<ol>
<li>The location marker header now displays the destination and speed(km/h value) of the train.</li>
<li>Users can set the destination(string of length 3) of the train.</li>
<li>Back-end deletes the records not updated for 5 minutes. So users won't have to deal with stale statuses.</li>
<li>Time interval between two communications with the back-end is user configurable through settings screen.</li>
</ol>
<p>Since the TrainMap needs both GPS and Mobile coverage to function correctly there are some areas where the statuses will not get updated. Also in the middle of train the GPS reception seems to be poor in some devices. But for overall application seems to be working OK. So far the application has been tested with few users/devices. And even from those few users getting feedback is harder than developing the application. :)</p>
<p><img src="/assets/trainmap/one_marker.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>You can get the beta version from the link below.</p>
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/apps/testing/com.kasungamlath.trainbuddy">play.google.com/apps/testing/com.kasungamlath.trainbuddy</a></p>
<p>I would love to hear about your experience even it's terrible. You can give me your feedback through,</p>
<ul>
<li>this page itself as a comment</li>
<li>this <a href="https://plus.google.com/communities/111728508620143036732">community page</a> reserved for this application testers</li>
<li>or even through social media/email is fine.</li>
</ul>
<p>Update (17/9/2015):[Web client of TrainMap]({{ site.baseurl }}/train-map/) is available now.</p>
<p>Happy train stalking...</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>TrainBuddy Loaction Tracking</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2015-08-23-TrainBuddy-Loaction-Tracking/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Just before the end of semester vacation I released a beta of train buddy with location tracking service. Once a user started it through the train map screen it'll access the location data of the device and will post them to the back-end once every predefined time interval.</p>
<p>For now it only posts latitude, longitude and user set destination code to the back-end. So the data is anonymous. Nothing is posted to link the location with the one who is reporting it. Also the data is not persistent in the back-end. While the service is running the same data record will be updated per user. And when the service is stopped that record will be deleted. So the data isn't historical and at the given time only the real time data is kept in back-end. Users can get these data from the train map screen. It will display as one marker per one location reported with the destination code as the title.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/location_tracking.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>For the service to post the location updates to the back-end both location and data connection should be active in the device. So this will cause a battery drain to some extent. I calculated 15% of battery level reduction with constantly running the service for one and half hours in a session. and when the signal reception is low the device get heated because the device radio is constantly trying to receive the signals. I think the battery drain and the heating issue can be reduced by fine tunning the interval of posting the data. It posts once per every 5 seconds in the current configuration. I only tested the system with only two devices. So have no idea how the system will work with multiple devices reporting the location at once.</p>
<p>Then there is also problem of getting locations when in middle of the train. Because GPS doesn't work well in indoors. It works great near doors and windows but in the middle of the train it struggles to connect to the GPS.</p>
<p>I'm hopping to release a production version once those kinks got sorted out. So guys you'll be able to stalk the trains in near future.</p>
<p>I also added push notifications in the beta version. it will be used for emergency notifications which is still being implemented.</p>
<p>Get the Beta from <a href="https://play.google.com/apps/testing/com.kasungamlath.trainbuddy">Google Play</a></p>
<p>UPDATE :It seems OK with reporting multiple locations.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>TrainBuddy offline search</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2015-08-01-TrainBuddy-offline-search/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Between writing a service to report the location and providing offline search I choose to implement offline search first. I did so because I thought that would be easier. But sadly I was wrong. I wanted to reuse the currently implemented components as much as possible. But that was proven to be harder than implementing them from the scratch. There were few reasons. I was using static methods, No dependency injection. So though I tried my best to loosely couple the components there were dependencies between components which makes it harder reusing them.</p>
<p>Finally I ended up refactoring the code and changing the flow of application internally. For user it'll look the same but inside there are some major changes. For example now most of the data is shared through the database. While this change causes a little performance reduction, now application is more robust and easier to maintain. Also you will experience a delay on the first run of the application because the database tables are created on the first run of the application. The <a href="https://github.com/satyan/sugar">library</a> I'm using to utilize the database is creating the tables at the first run of the application and it does so in the main thread. Hence the first start up delay. There is a talk to do that in a separate thread, but until then the delay will remain since I can't control it in the application code.</p>
<p>So now moving to the good part. To use the offline search you'll have to provide the two stations you frequently travel in-between. For example the nearest station to your home and nearest station to the work place. After you set it up the offline caching will start and will save the schedule between those two stations for the coming week. And once finished you can search the schedule between the two stations anytime while staying offline. Time filters also work. (I limited the caching to two stations because that'll address the most of the use cases without confusing the user while keeping the resource use both in devices and API to the minimum).</p>
<p><img src="/assets/offline_search.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>The offline cache will updated once a week. To do this it checks the date of the cache and network availability at the start of application and if the conditions are satisfied it'll run the cache update. Cache will also be updated if you change a frequent station (in settings). There are few other use cases remain to consider when to update the cache. And hopefully they will be addressed in the next production release. This feature is live in the current beta (v1.3). As usually you are welcome to try it. Also I changed the beta testing method to &quot;open&quot;. So you'll be able to access the beta version through the following link regardless you were a member of the testing community. You can always contact me with suggestions and bug reports.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading.</p>
<p>tl;dr</p>
<p>Train Buddy beta now works even in offline mode.</p>
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/apps/testing/com.kasungamlath.trainbuddy">Beta version on Google Play</a></p>
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kasungamlath.trainbuddy">Stable version on Google Play</a></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dimple Hacker News Reader</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2015-07-24-Dimple-Hacker-News-Reader/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>In the same after exam break that I changed the TrainBuddy (my other android app)'s visual design, I made some changes to Hacker News reader.( In fact changed it's name too).</p>
<p><img src="assets/dimple.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>Inspired by the Google Now Story cards design I changed the design of news Item. Altering what I already had was easy. Loading the thumbnail image was the question.</p>
<p>After bit of Googling and tinkering I hacked my own web app to return a 192x192 thumbnail when an url is provided. First it'll try to get the image from web page, if failed will look for apple-touch-icon of the web site, which is basically the site favicon with higher resolution. If that too fails it will return a transparent image. So the bottom line is server will always return a thumbnail no matter what the provided url. I did it like this is to stop the repeated retry requests of ION (image loading library), I used to load the images. The app will first fill the thumbnail placeholder with a random color and first letter of the title. then ION will load the thumbnail from the server on top of that. So even the server failed to find a image from the url, the news Item will look good.</p>
<p>In the previous setup. Whole item list for listview is populated at the beginning with news index values. Then separate items are loaded from the HN API at the time when list items are created. The way android lists work is they only keep items in memory that are visible to user and additional two in memory, one in top and one. Loading items in this way is OK when the data is stored locally. But when data is coming from an external API this is not OK. Users will have to wait until the news item is retrieved and loaded. The app will feel slow and laggy. Not a good UX. So I ended up retrieving news items as the scrolling happens, 20 items at once. And immediately send API requests to these new items. So when the items are created for user the data will hopefully be present in device. And only if this fails user can manually load the items once they were visible to them.</p>
<p>I also added support for sharing items. So now the long press on Item title or long press on thumbnail will open the dialog to share. And news Item title + url will be passed with that share intent. Normal click on title and thumbnail will open the article in device browser while click on 2nd raw which contains the domain age and user will open the article in hn web site where user can read the conversation about the article.</p>
<p>Of course there is still a long way to go for this app. I still have number of functions to implement. But before start doing that I would like to get feed back on the things I already implemented and get them right. Plus I have no idea how the server will hold. So far it served only me.</p>
<p>I have released the application for beta users. You are welcome to join this <a href="https://plus.google.com/communities/118167818139031156233">G+ community</a>, follow the steps listed there, and enjoy the beta version.</p>
<p>Here is the link to application in <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kasungamlath.hackernews">Google play</a>. If you are not a beta user you'll only see the old version of the application.(Even if you joined the above G+ page it could take some time to access the beta version, as notified by Google. So join the community install the old version and once your beta state is activated, you'll get an update notification)</p>
<p>You can provide your valuable feedback in here or in <a href="https://plus.google.com/communities/118167818139031156233">G+ page</a>.</p>
<p>tl;dr</p>
<p>Dimple is a beautiful(yet incomplete) Hacker News client.</p>
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/apps/testing/com.kasungamlath.hackernews">Beta version on Google Play</a></p>
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kasungamlath.hackernews">Stable version on Google Play</a></p>
<p>Happy Reading !!!</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>TrainBuddy New Look</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2015-07-24-TrainBuddy-New-Look/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>After the semester exams I got an break for few weeks. So I took that time to do a thing I wanted to do for a while now.</p>
<p>TrainBuddy was already looking nice. It's already the best looking kid in the block of train schedule apps (in my opinion). But that doesn't mean It can't look nicer. So I took some time, read google design guides, checked the new support library and made some changes.</p>
<p>There are few notable changes.</p>
<p>1.Navigational view.</p>
<p>The previous way of navigating (using the spinner) was kind of looked out of place, provided I needed add few options to the user (more options on the way). So the navigational view was the right choice. So with the support of android support library I added a navigational view to the app. Adding this was harder than I thought. Mainly because the use of One activity architecture. So I had to manually handle all the fragment transitions. So though the code is now full of hacks it works.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/trainBuddy_new_look/navigation_new.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>2.Typography in input providing view.</p>
<p>With the navigational view following the google design guidelines now the input providing view looked alien. I tried adding few icons. But it didn't jell. So ended up changing the typography. And the new swap button has a icon now.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/trainBuddy_new_look/user_in_new.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>3.Result view layout and emission of journey detail view.(RIP detail view)</p>
<p>Here in list items I tried to get the look and feel of google inbox application. Also added the frequency and class availability to the list item. I also added the journey details to the result list view. because there isn't much additional detail to view in a separate view after adding the frequency and class availability to the list item. And also journey detail is same for all the results per query. And the journey detail view was ugly and I couldn't think of a way to fix it.</p>
<p>Another notable thing here is the view at the top of the window. Though it looks like the action bar it isn't. It's a linear layout with a navigation button. It's because I couldn't find a way to change the action bar layout for only one fragment. I was trying to add a collapsing toolbar here. But couldn't find a way without changing the application architecture. I think the reason is the one activity architecture as I explained in previous post.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/trainBuddy_new_look/result_list_new.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>4.Addition of help &amp; feedback view.</p>
<p>Since the list item layout got little complex here I added some explanations about it and provided means for users to contact the developer(that's me ;)) through the application. Also added a link to rate the application.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/trainBuddy_new_look/help.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>Sadly I had to set the minimum Sdk level to 14 since some of the features are not available below sdk level 14. So this version will only be available for devices with ICS (Ice Cream Sandwich) and above.</p>
<p>All these changes are available for beta users now. If you are not a beta user yet join <a href="https://plus.google.com/communities/111728508620143036732">here</a> and enjoy the new look. Non beta users will have to wait some time for the new release since there are few minor bugs to iron out.</p>
<p>If you haven't try TrainBuddy yet get it from the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kasungamlath.trainbuddy">Google play</a></p>
<p>Happy commuting !!!</p>
<p>UPDATE(28 July 2015) :Now available for all the users.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Android Wireless Debugging</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2015-07-24-Android-Wireless-Debugging/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Few weeks ago I came to know about this cool feature of wireless ADB (Android Debug Bridge). Following method doesn't need root access to device. If you have done any development in android I'm sure you already have used adb. As the name suggests it let you build a bridge between computer and android device. So you can control your device from the computer. adb has many uses other than debugging. just issue command adb to find out all of them. If you haven't already installed adb you'll have to install adb before continuing. On ubuntu or ubuntu variation command to install adb is &quot;sudo apt-get install android-tools-adb&quot;.</p>
<p>To do this your computer and device has to be in a same wireless network. if you are not create a wireless access point from computer and from your device, connect to that access point. then connect the device through a usb cable to computer and follow these steps</p>
<p>1.Make sure adb is running in USB mode on host.</p>
<p>$ adb usb</p>
<p>2.Connect to the device over USB. (your devices should be listed as output of following command)</p>
<p>$ adb devices</p>
<p>3.Restart host adb in tcpip mode.</p>
<p>$ adb tcpip 5555</p>
<p>4.Find out the IP address of the Android device: Settings -&gt; About tablet -&gt; Status -&gt; IP address. Remember the IP address, of the form #.#.#.#.</p>
<p>5.Connect adb host to device:</p>
<p>$ adb connect #.#.#.#</p>
<p>6.Remove USB cable from device, and confirm you can still access device:(if the device is not listed issue the command in 5th step again)</p>
<p>$ adb devices</p>
<p>if you got unable to connect error in step 5, try the same connect command few times. If the error is persitent kill the adb server &quot;$ adb kill-server&quot; and start again from step 1. If you still get the error try different port in step 3, for example &quot;$ adb tcpip 5556&quot;. Then you got to change the connect command in step 4 to &quot;$ adb connect #.#.#.#:5556&quot;.</p>
<p>Happy debugging !!!</p>
<p><img src="/assets/debugging.gif" alt="" /></p>
<p>Source :<a href="http://developer.android.com/tools/help/adb.html">http://developer.android.com/tools/help/adb.html</a></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>One activity to rule them all</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2015-07-21-One-activity-to-rule-them-all/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>This is a post about current architecture of the Train Buddy application. It has only one activity and multiple fragments for work and UI. Communication done via interfaces. Fragments are independent with each and they all communicate through the activity. It makes it easier to debug and maintain the code. loosely coupled, high cohesive classes is considered as a good in SE. Also It's easier to share the data structures, easier to save the state through the life cycle of the application. And it makes it possible to keep the application logic in that single class.</p>
<p>While this structure has it's own perks there are some problems too. Like all things in world this also is a trade of between good and bad things. As the comlexity/size of the application grows it will inevitably result a spaghetti code in the main activity. which could be lethal for the well being of the application. As a solution for this I think using dependency injection could result much shorter code. But I haven't tried it yet. And also all the fragment transitions had to manually handled while with separate activities they were handled by the OS, here it's not the case. so providing a sound navigation for the user is just short of a nightmare. when you got a navigation drawer it only cause more trouble. because navigation drawer is a part of the application bar and application bar is a part of the activity. There is only one appbar for the entire application. It's a good thing if the navigation drawer is allowed everywhere but that just confuses the user. so it's just shown in the top level UI fragments. and to handle this I had done fare number of ugly hacks. I'm pretty sure there had to be a better way which is still not known to me. since you have only one app bar if you want to change it's layout in some fragments(like having a collapsing toolbar) you are just out of luck.</p>
<p>So as you can see the bad out weights the good in my post. Mainly because I'm using it currently. People tend to see bad things of things they have and good things in things they haven't. The effect of green grass. So the bottom line here in my opinion, this structure is great if your application is simple but not so great when it grows.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/one_ring.jpg%22" alt="" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>HNYC v0</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2015-06-21-HNYC-v0/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Today I came upon a android application with material design to read xkcd comics which is still in alpha stage. Interesting point is that it's been released just yesterday and had more that 100 installs. And here I am with trainbuddy app (which is obviously much nicer and more useful :)) which released for 2 months by now and with the same number of installations. I think reason is xkcd app has much biger audience (7 billion +) than mine (20 million) since it's a local app. So the ratio of audience is 350:1.</p>
<p>In light of these new findings I thought of giving a try with a bigger audience with my already released (because of a matter of CV), but yet only known to me (because of 0 marketing) HNYC app. So I updated the store listing and shared the link for this post. Who knows may be I'll ride a wave end up in front page of HN. :)</p>
<p>About the app, It has few nice features like pull to refresh, swipe to change the view, (kind of) infinite scroll, Auto hiding action bar. Sexy material design. And it uses new API at https://hacker-news.firebaseio.com/. Also this is only the beginning of this app. You can read more from Google play listing.</p>
<div align="center"> <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kasungamlath.hackernews">
  <img alt="Get it on Google Play"
       src="https://developer.android.com/images/brand/en_generic_rgb_wo_60.png" />
</a>
</div>
<p>Update 1 : I shared the app in hn site and got some feedback. Will post in reddit after including the suggestions I recieved.</p>
<p>Update 2 : Updated the app. But reddit says I have to wait a month before posting in reddit.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/hnyc_framed_v04.png" alt="" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Forking Youtube dl Web</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2015-06-19-Forking-Youtube-dl-Web/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>After playing with heroku for few weeks while wrestling with my fb app for research, I built a web app I always wanted. It was easier than I thought. All I had to do was editing few files in few different projects and firing up a heroku app. So now I got my own web app to download videos from various different sites. There are few bugs to iron out. But the app seems stable enough to use.</p>
<p>You too are welcome to try it out :<a href="http://ytd.kasungamlath.com/" target="_blank">http://ytd.kasungamlath.com/</a></p>
<p><img src="/assets/ytd.png" alt="" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Train Buddy 100 installs</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2015-06-18-Train-Buddy-100-installs/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>After 2 months since public release Train Buddy now have more than 100 total installs. I know it's not much. But it's just another app (yet), to view train schedule in Srilanka with a updated UI. So thank you, each and every one who installed the train buddy.</p>
<p>Train Buddy never went viral. Always just few installs per day. But the growth was steady. The most used app in this category has around 100,000 installations. But it's released by ICTA and kind of the &quot;official&quot; app. 2nd most popular app has about 10,000 intallations. So the good new is only 16 more years to catchup with that in this rate of installations.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/train-buddy-100.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>But the most important thing is now the app has completed the goal for it's 2nd iteration. Which will enable viewing the status of trains when you are &quot;not on board&quot;. With the vacation coming up in next month, I think this could be completed before the end of this July (if my research work allows me, fingers crossed). As usual beta testers will get the new version first. So if you are not joined yet join <a href="https://plus.google.com/communities/111728508620143036732">this community</a>, download <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kasungamlath.trainbuddy">the application</a> and be ready to have the train status at your fingertips anytime you want (hopefully).</p>
<p>PS :You can request features, post suggestions and give feedback through <a href="https://plus.google.com/communities/111728508620143036732">the community page</a> too.</p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Train Buddy v1</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2015-04-17-Train-Buddy-v1/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>After few months of beta testing, today I have released the Train Buddy app to public. Train Buddy is a android app for getting the train schedule of Srilankan trains and view the current status (location and speed) of the train. You can learn more from the Google play <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kasungamlath.trainbuddy">app description</a>.</p>
<div align="center"><a  href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kasungamlath.trainbuddy">
  <img alt="Get it on Google Play"
       src="https://developer.android.com/images/brand/en_generic_rgb_wo_60.png" />
</a></div>
<p>If you are interested in testing the future versions of app please join <a href="http://goo.gl/VX6BLe">this community page</a>. Members of this community will always get the latest functions first.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/a9dfe8fd-bee2-487a-9e4e-5f59e1a7aec5.png" alt="" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Create a blog like this</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2015-04-17-How-Create-a-blog-like-this/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Process requires a github account (which you can have for free) and about 30 mins of free time. This is made possible by FOSS tool called <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">jekyll</a>.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Sign up for free github account (if you haven't already).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fork <a href="https://github.com/barryclark/jekyll-now">jekyll-now</a> repository. (Just press the fork button on top right of the page).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Rename the forked repository to &quot;yourusername.github.io&quot;.(you can access rename from settings page of the repository) For example if your username is &quot;abcd&quot; your repository name should be &quot;abcd.github.io&quot;.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Now visit &quot;http://yourusername.github.io&quot;. You should find your blog you just created there (It could be take up to 10 mins as Github suggests). If not check the repository settings page. If there is a error you could see that in page with built error notification.</p>
<p>Easy right?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Now edit the &quot;_config.yml&quot; file in your repository to make that blog personalized (this file is pretty self-explanatory). And commit the changes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Publishing the first post. Edit the &quot;/_posts/2014-3-3-Hello-World.md&quot; by replacing the placeholder content with your own.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you own a domain name edit the &quot;CNAME&quot; file and got to your domain name registrar and add a CNAME DNS record. So you can visit the blog you just created in &quot;www.yourdomainname.com&quot;.</p>
<p>type: CNAME</p>
<p>host: www.yourdomainname.com</p>
<p>answer: yourusername.github.io</p>
<p>TTL: 300</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Now you better learn on git(if you haven't already) in order to continue adding blog posts.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>This is the <a href="http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2014/08/01/build-blog-jekyll-github-pages/">link</a> for the guide I followed which is more explanatory.</p>
<p><a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a></p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/">Github</a></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Train Buddy Beta</title>
<link>https://kasungamlath.com/blog/2015-04-16-Train-Buddy-Beta/</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>
<p>Android app for getting the train schedule of Srilankan trains and view the current status (location and speed) of the train (Unfortunately this status function only works when you are in the train, yet). Read app description on Google play for more details.</p>
<p>Link to the testing community of the app (you are welcome to join) : <a href="http://goo.gl/VX6BLe">http://goo.gl/VX6BLe</a></p>
<p>Link to the app (only available for members of the above  community. will be available for all once the app passed the testing phase) : <a href="http://goo.gl/pzyJP6">http://goo.gl/pzyJP6</a></p>
<p><img src="/assets/trainbuddy-playstore.png" alt="" /></p>

</p>
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>


</channel>
</rss>
